<?xml version="1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:reg="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/profile/regap/"
    xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#">

<!-- Scheme: ISBD Media Type -->
    <skos:ConceptScheme rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype">
        <dc:title>ISBD Media Type</dc:title>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1001"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1002"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1003"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1004"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1008"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1009"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1005"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1006"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1010"/>
        <skos:hasTopConcept rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1007"/>
    </skos:ConceptScheme>

<!-- Concept: audio  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1001" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1211"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store recorded sound, designed for use with a playback device such as a turntable, audiocassette player, CD player, MP3 player, or iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">Includes media used to store digitally encoded as well as analogue sound.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medios utilizados para almacenar sonido grabado, diseñado para su uso con un dispositivo de reproducción como un tocadiscos, reproductor de audiocasete, reproductor de CD, reproductor de MP3 o iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="es">Incluye los medios utilizados para almacenar tanto sonido codificado digitalmente como sonido analógico. </skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di suoni registrati, che si usano con dispositivi per la riproduzione (playback device), come un giradischi, un lettore per audiocassette, un lettore CD, un lettore MP3, o un iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="it">Include i supporti per la memorizzazione di suoni codificati sia in forma digitale sia in forma analogica.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">аудио</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на звукозапис, предназначени за ползване с възпроизвеждащи устройства като грамофон, касетофон, CD плеър, MP3 плеър или iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="bg">Включва средства за съхраняване както на цифрово кодиран, така и на аналогов звук.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">аудио</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje snimljenog zvuka, namenjenog za korišćenje pomoću uređaja za reprodukciju, kao što je gramofon, kasetofon, CD plejer, MP3 plejer ili iPod. </skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="sr">Podrazumeva i medije koji se koriste za pohranjivanje digitalno i analogno kodiranog zvuka.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">音频</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存录音的载体，设计要用转盘、卡式磁带播放器、激光唱片播放器、MP3播放器或iPod等回放设备。</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="zh">既包括储存数字编码声音的载体，也包括储存模拟声音的载体。</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami ierakstītās mūzikas glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar atskaņošanas ierīci, kā piem., atskaņotāju, kasešu magnetofonu, CD atskaņotāju, MP3 atskaņotāju vai iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="lv">Ietver medijus/datnešus, kas izmantojami digitāli kodētas, kā arī analogas skaņas glabāšanai.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">audio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker du son enregistré et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un dispositif de lecture tel que platine, lecteur de cassette audio, de CD, MP3 ou iPod.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="fr">Ce terme recouvre des supports utilisés pour stocker du son encodé de manière numérique aussi bien qu’analogique.</skos:scopeNote>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: electronic  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1002" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1212"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">electronic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store electronic files, designed for use with a computer.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">Includes media that are accessed remotely through file servers, as well as direct-access media such as computer tapes and disks.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">electrónico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio utilizado para almacenar los archivos electrónicos, diseñado para su uso con un ordenador.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="es">Incluye los medios a los que se accede de forma remota a través de servidores de archivos, así como medios de acceso directo, tales como cintas y discos de ordenador.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">elektronički</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">elettronico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di file elettronici, da usare con un computer.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="it">Include i supporti ad accesso remoto via server e i supporti ad accesso diretto, come nastri e dischi magnetici per computer.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">електронен</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на електронни файлове, предназначени за ползване с компютър.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="bg">Включва както средства, достъпни от отдалечени сървъри, така и средства с пряк достъп като компютърни ленти и дискове.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">электронный</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения электронных файлов, предназначенные для использования с помощью компьютера.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="ru">Включают как средства, доступные с отдаленных серверов, так и средства прямого доступа, такие как компьютерные ленты и диски.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">elektronski</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje elektronskih dokumenata, namenjenih za korišćenje pomoću računara.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="sr">Podrazumeva medije kojima se pristupa daljinski preko servera, kao i one sa direktnim pristupom, kao što su računarske trake i diskete.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">电子</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存电子文件的载体，设计要用计算机来使用。</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="zh">既包括通过远程文件服务器访问的载体，也包括计算机磁带和磁盘等直接访问的载体。</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">elektronisks</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami elektronisko datņu glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar datoru.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="lv">Ietver medijus/datnešus, kas pieejami no attālinātiem datņu serveriem, kā arī no tiešās piekļuves, kā datorlentes un diski.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">électronique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker des fichiers électroniques et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un ordinateur.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="fr">Ce terme recouvre aussi bien des supports accessibles à distance par des serveurs que des supports en accès local comme des bandes ou des disques.</skos:scopeNote>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: microform  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1003" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1213"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">microform</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store reduced-size images, not readable to the human eye, and designed for use with a device such as a microfilm or microfiche reader.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">Includes both transparent and opaque micrographic media.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">microforma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio utilizado para almacenar imágenes de tamaño reducido, no legible para el ojo humano y diseñado para su uso con un dispositivo como un lector de microfilm o microficha.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="es">Incluye tanto los medios micrográficos transparentes como los opacos.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">mikrooblik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">microforma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di immagini di dimensioni ridotte, non leggibili dall’occhio umano, da usare con dispositivi come un lettore di microfilm o di microfiche.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="it">Include i supporti micrografici per trasparenti e per opachi.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">микроформа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на намалени изображения, които не могат да се четат с невъоръжено око и са предназначени за използване с помощта на устройство като апарат за четене на микрофилм или микрофиш.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="bg">Включва както прозрачни, така и непрозрачни микрографски средства.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">микроформа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения уменьшенных изображений, не читаемых человеческим глазом и предназначенные для использования с помощью устройств, таких как аппарат для чтения микрофильмов или микрофиш.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="ru">Включает как прозрачные, так и непрозрачные микрографические средства.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">mikrooblik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje umanjenih slika koje ne mogu da se čitaju golim okom i namenjene za korišćenje pomoću uređaja kao što su čitač mikrofilma i čitač mikrofiša.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="sr">Podrazumeva prozirne i neprozirne mikro medije.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">缩微</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存肉眼不可阅读的缩小尺寸图像的载体，设计要用缩微胶卷阅读器或者缩微平片阅读器来使用。</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="zh">包括透明的和不透明的缩微载体。</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">mikroforma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami pamazinātu attēlu glabāšanai, kas nav labi salasāmi un paredzēti lietot ar ierīci, kā mikrofilmu vai mikrofišu lasītāju.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="lv">Ietver gan caurspīdīgus un gan gaismas necaurlaidīgus mikrografikas medijus/datnešus.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">microforme</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker des images en réduction non lisibles à l’œil nu, et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un dispositif tel qu’un lecteur de microfilm ou de microfiche. </skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="fr">Ce terme recouvre des supports micrographiques aussi bien transparents qu’opaques.</skos:scopeNote>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: microscopic  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1004" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1214"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">microscopic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store minute objects, designed for use with a device such as a microscope to reveal details invisible to the naked eye.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">microscópico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio utilizado para almacenar objetos diminutos, diseñados para su uso con un dispositivo como un microscopio para revelar detalles invisibles a simple vista.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">mikroskopski</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">microscopico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di oggetti minuti, da usare con dispositivi come un microscopio per rivelare dettagli non visibili a occhio nudo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">микроскопски</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на миниатюрни обекти, предназначени за използване с устройство като микроскоп, за да се видят детайли, които са невидими за невъоръжено око.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">микроскопический</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения мелких объектов, предназначенные для использования с помощью устройств, таких как микроскоп, чтобы можно было увидеть детали, недоступные невооруженному глазу.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">mikroskopski</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje sitnih objekata namenjenih za korišćenje pomoću uređaja kao što je mikroskop kako bi mogli da se vide detalji nevidljivi golim okom.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">显微</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存微型物体的载体，设计要用显微镜等设备来揭示肉眼不可见的细节。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">mikroskopisks</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami ļoti sīku objektu glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar tādu ierīci kā mikroskops, lai atklātu detaļas, kas nav saskatāmas ar neapbruņotu aci.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">microscopique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker de minuscules objets, et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un dispositif tel qu’un microscope afin de révéler des détails invisibles à l’œil nu.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: multiple media  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1008" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1218"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">multiple media</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media where three or more media types are applicable.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">múltiples medios</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio en el que son aplicables tres o más tipos de medios.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">viševrsni mediji</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">supporti multipli</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">различни средства</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">разные средства</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">viševrsni oblik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">多载体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">对于由混合载体组成、三种或更多载体类型适用的资源。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporto per il quale tre o più tipi di supporto sono applicabili.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">multisupport</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Terme utilisé pour des ressources composées de différents supports, auxquelles s’appliquent au moins trois types de médiation.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: other media  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1009" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1219"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">other media</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media other than audio, electronic, microform, microscopic, projected, stereographic, or video, or multiple media.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">otros medios</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio diferente al audio, electrónico, microforma, microscópico, proyectado, estereográfico, vídeo o múltiples medios.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">drugi mediji</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">altri supporti</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">други средства</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">другое средство</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">drugi medij</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">其他载体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporto diverso da  audio, elettronico, microforma, microscopico, proiettato, stereografico, video  o supporti multipli.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">type de médiation non défini</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Terme utilisé pour des ressources dont le type de médiation est autre que : audio, électronique, microforme, microscopique, projeté(e), stéréographique, vidéo ou multisupport. </skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: projected  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1005" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1215"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">projected</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store moving or still images, designed for use with a projection device such as a motion picture film projector, slide projector, or overhead projector.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">Includes media designed to project both two-dimensional and three-dimensional images.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">proyectado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medios utilizados para almacenar imágenes fijas o en movimiento, diseñado para su uso con un dispositivo de proyección como un proyector de película de cine en movimiento, proyector de diapositivas o retroproyector.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="es">Incluye los medios diseñados tanto para imágenes bidimensionales como tridimensionales.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">projiciran</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">proiettato</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di immagini fisse o in movimento, da usare con dispositivi per la proiezione, come un proiettore di film, un proiettore di diapositive, una lavagna luminosa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="it">Include i supporti per la proiezione di immagini bidimensionali e tridimensionali.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">проекционен</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на движещи се или неподвижни изображения, предназначени за ползване с устройство за прожектиране като проектор за филми, диапроектор или проекционен апарат.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="bg">Включва средства, предназначени за прожектиране както на двуизмерни, така и на триизмерни изображения.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">проекционный</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения неподвижного или движущегося изображений, предназначенные для использования с помощью проекционного оборудования, такого как кинопроектор, диапроектор или проекционный аппарат.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="ru">Включаются средства, предназначенные для проецирования как двухмерных, так и трехмерных изображений.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">projektovan</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje pokretnih ili nepokretnih slika, namenjenih za korišćenje pomoću uređaja za projektovanje, kao što je kinoprojektor, dijaprojektor ili grafoskop.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="sr">Podrazumeva medije namenjene za projektovanje i dvodimenzionalnih i trodimenzionalnih slika.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">投影</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存运动或静止图像的载体，设计要用电影胶片投影仪、幻灯投影仪等投影设备来使用。</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">包括设计用于投射二维和三维图像的载体。</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">projicējams</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami nekustīgo vai kustīgo attēlu glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar projicēšanas ierīci, kā projektoru, diaprojektoru vai kodoskopu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="lv">Ietver medijus/datnešus, kas paredzēti gan divdimensiju, gan trīsdimensiju attēlu projicēšanai.</skos:scopeNote>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: stereographic  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1006" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1216"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">stereographic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store pairs of still images, designed for use with a device such as a stereoscope or stereograph viewer to give the effect of three dimensions.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">estereográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medios utilizados para almacenar parejas de imágenes fijas, diseñados para su uso con un dispositivo como un estereoscopio o visor estereográfico para dar efecto tridimensional.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">stereografski</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">stereografico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di coppie di immagini fisse, da usare con dispositivi come un visore stereoscopico o stereografico per produrre l’effetto della tridimensionalità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">стереографски</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на двойки неподвижни изображения с устройство като стереоскоп или стереограф, за да се създаде ефект на триизмерност.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">стереографический</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения парного неподвижного изображения, предназначенные для использования с помощью устройств, таких как стереоскоп или стереографический аппарат для получения эффекта трехмерности.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">stereografski</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje parova nepokretnih slika, namenjenih za korišćenje pomoću uređaja kao što je stereoskop ili stereograf kako bi se postigao efekat trodimenzionalnosti.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">立体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存成对静止图像的载体，设计要用立体镜或立体画观看器等设备来使用，以产生三维效果。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">stereogrāfisks</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami nekustīgu pāra attēlu glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar stereoskopu vai stereogrāfa ierīci, lai sniegtu trīsdimensiju efektu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">stéréoscopique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker des paires d’images fixes, et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un dispositif tel qu’un stéréoscope ou un visualiseur de stéréogrammes afin de donner l’illusion des trois dimensions.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: unmediated  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1010" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/3372"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">unmediated</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media for which no mediation device is necessary.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">sin mediación</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio que no requiere dispositivo de intermediación</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">neposredovan</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">senza mediazione</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">без устройство</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporto per il quale non è necessario nessun dispositivo di mediazione.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: video  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype/T1007" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/1217"/>
      <skos:topConceptOf rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/isbd/terms/mediatype"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">video</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Media used to store moving or still images, designed for use with a playback device such as a videocassette player or DVD player.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="en">Includes media used to store digitally encoded as well as analogue images.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">vídeo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Medio utilizado para almacenar imágenes fijas o en movimiento, diseñado para su uso con un dispositivo de reproducción como un reproductor de cintas de vídeo o un reproductor de DVD.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="es">Incluye los medios utilizados para almacenar tanto imágenes codificadas digitalmente como imágenes analógicas.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">video</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">video</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Supporti per la memorizzazione di immagini fisse o in movimento, da usare con dispositivi per la riproduzione (playback device), come un lettore di videocassette o di DVD.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="it">Include i supporti per la memorizzazione di immagini codificate sia in forma digitale sia in forma analogica.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">видео</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Средства, използвани за съхраняване на движещи се или неподвижни изображения, предназначени за използване с възпроизвеждащо устройство като видео или DVD плеър.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="bg">Включва средства за съхраняване както на цифрово кодирани, така и на аналогови изображения.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">видео</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Средства, используемые для хранения неподвижного или движущегося изображения, предназначенные для использования с помощью воспроизводящих устройств, таких как кассетный видео плеер или DVD плеер.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="ru">Включают средства, используемые для хранения изображений как в цифровом, так и в аналоговом формате.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">video</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Medij koji se koristi za pohranjivanje pokretnih ili nepokretnih slika, namenjenih za korišćenje pomoću uređaja za reprodukovanje, kao što je video plejer ili DVD plejer.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="sr">Podrazumeva i medije koji se koriste za pohranjivanje digitalno kodiranih kao i analognih slika.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">视频</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用于储存运动或静止图像的载体，设计要用卡式录像带播放器或DVD播放器等设备来使用。</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="zh">包括储存数字编码的和模拟的图像的载体。</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">video</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Mediji/datneši, izmantojami kustīgu vai nekustīgu attēlu glabāšanai, paredzēti lietot ar atskaņošanas ierīci, kā video kasešu atskaņotāju vai DVD atskaņotāju.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="lv">Ietver medijus/datnešus, kas izmantojami digitāli kodēto, kā arī analogo attēlu glabāšanai.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">vidéo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Support utilisé pour stocker des images fixes ou animées, et conçu pour être utilisé au moyen d’un dispositif de lecture tel qu’un lecteur de cassette vidéo ou de DVD.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="fr">Ce terme recouvre des supports conçus pour stocker de l’image encodée de manière numérique aussi bien qu’analogique.</skos:scopeNote>
    </skos:Concept>

<!-- Status properties used in this document  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Published</skos:prefLabel>
    </skos:Concept>

</rdf:RDF>
