<?xml version="1.0" encoding = "UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:reg="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/profile/regap/"
    xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#">

<!-- Scheme: Multilingual dictionary of cataloguing terms and concepts (MulDiCat) -->
    <skos:ConceptScheme rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat">
        <dc:title>Multilingual dictionary of cataloguing terms and concepts (MulDiCat)</dc:title>
    </skos:ConceptScheme>

<!-- Concept: Access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4675"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A name, term, code, etc., through which bibliographic or authority data is searched and identified.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Emër, term, kod etj., përmes të cilit kërkohen dhe identifikohen të dhënat bibliografike ose ato të termave të njësuar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول – اسم، مصطلح، رمز، الخ، والتي من خلالها يتم الاسترجاع والتعرف على تسجيلة ببليوغرافية أو استنادية أو إحالة مرجعية.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Име, наименование, термин, код и др., чрез които се търси и открива библиографски или контролен запис.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Nom, terme, codi, etc. per mitjà del qual se cerquen i s’identifiquen dades bibliogràfiques i d’autoritat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用以检索和识别书目数据或规范数据的一个名称、术语、代码等。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Ime, naziv, kod itd. pod kojim će se pronaći i identificirati bibliografski ili autorizirani podaci.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Jméno, termín, kód atd., jejichž prostřednictvím je bibliografický či autoritní údaj vyhledán a identifikován.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Nimi, termi, koodi yms., jonka avulla bibliografinen tai auktoriteettitietue voidaan etsiä ja identifioida.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d'accès</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Nom, terme, code, etc., sous lequel des données bibliographiques ou d'autorité sont recherchées et identifiées.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Sucheinstieg</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Name, Begriff, Code etc., unter dem bibliografische Daten oder Normdaten gesucht und identifiziert werden können.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Nome, termine, codice, ecc. mediante il quale il dato bibliografico o di autorità è ricercato e identificato.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">それにより書誌データまたは典拠データを検索し、識別する名称、用語、コード等。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지데이터나 전거데이터를 탐색하고 식별하기 위한 이름이나 용어, 부호 등</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Personvārds/nosaukums, apzīmējums, kods u.tml., pēc kura iespējams sameklēt un identificēt bibliogrāfiskos vai autoritatīvos datus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vardas, terminas, kodas ir t. t., pagal kurį ieškomi ir
identifikuojami bibliografiniai arba autoritetiniai duomenys.
</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Nazwa, termin, kod itd., za pomocą którego można
wyszukiwać i identyfikować dane bibliograficzne lub wzorcowe.
</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Nome, termo, código, etc., pelo qual se pesquisa e identifica um registo bibliográfico, de autoridade ou referência.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Точка доступа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Имя (наименование), термин, код и т.п., с помощью которого могут быть найдены  и идентифицированы библиографические или авторитетные данные.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Ime, naziv, termin, kod i drugo, pod kojim će biti pronađen i identifikovan bibliografski ili normativni podatak.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Meno, termín, kód atď., prostredníctvom ktorého je bibliografický alebo autoritatívny údaj vyhľadaný a identifikovaný.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Ime, pojem, kodiran podatek itn., s pomočjo katerega iščemo bibliografske ali normativne podatke in jih identificiramo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un nombre, término, código, etc. por el que se busca e indentifican datos bibliográficos o de autoridad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Ett namn, term, kod etc. med hjälp av vilket bibliografisk data och auktoritetsdata kan sökas och identifieras.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึง</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อ คำศัพท์ รหัส และอื่น ๆ ที่ใช้ในการค้นหาและระบุรายการบรรณานุกรม รายการควบคุม หรือรายการอ้างอิง</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tên, thuật ngữ, mã,… được xác định để tìm kiếm trong dữ liệu thư mục và dữ liệu tác giả.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AdditionalAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#EssentialAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#UncontrolledAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Additional access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AdditionalAccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4676"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Additional access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An access point that may be used in addition to the essential access points to enhance the retrieval of bibliographic or authority data.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse shtesë</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse që mund të përdoret përveç pikës hyrëse kryesore për të zgjeruar kërkimin e të dhënave bibliografike ose atyre të termave të njësuar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول الإضافية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقطة وصول يمكن أن تستخدم بالإضافة إلى نقاط الوصول الأساسية لزيادة استرجاع التسجيلات الببليوجرافية والاستنادية.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Допълнителна точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Точка за достъп, която може да се използва като допълнение към основните точки за достъп, за да се увеличи извличането на библиографски и контролни данни.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés addicional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés que es pot utilitzar a més a més dels punts d’accés essencials per millorar la recuperació de dades bibliogràfiques o d’autoritat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">附加检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">可作为基本检索点的补充，用以增强书目数据或规范数据检索的一种检索点。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Dodatna pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pristupnica koja se može upotrebljavati uz neophodne pristupnice u svrhu poboljšanja pronalaženja bibliografskih i autoriziranih podataka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Doplňkový selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Selekční údaj, který lze použít k doplnění základních selekčních údajů pro usnadnění vyhledávání bibliografických či autoritních údajů.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Lisätty hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Hakutieto, jota voidaan käyttää ensisijaisen hakutiedon lisäksi tehostamassa bibliografisen tai auktoriteettitiedon löytämistä.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès supplémentaire</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès qui peut être utilisé en plus des points d’accès essentiels pour faciliter la recherche des données bibliographiques ou d’autorité.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Sucheinstieg, der zusätzlich zum notwendigen Sucheinstieg genutzt werden kann, um das Retrieval von bibliografischen Daten und Normdaten zu verbessern.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Zusätzlicher Sucheinstieg</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso aggiuntivo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso che può essere usato in aggiunta ai punti di accesso indispensabile per migliorare il recupero dei dati bibliografici o di autorità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">付加的アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">書誌データまたは典拠データの検索を向上させるため、中核的アクセスポイントに加えて使用することがあるアクセスポイント</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">부차적 접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지데이터나 전거데이터의 검색을 확장하기 위하여 필수 접근점 이외에 추가로 사용되는 접근점</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Papildu piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Piekļuves punkts, ko var izmantot papildus svarīgākajiem piekļuves punktiem, lai paplašinātu bibliogrāfisko vai autoritatīvo datu izguves iespējas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Papildomas kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Kreipties elementas, kuris gali būti vartojamas papildomai prie esminių kreipties elementų bibliografinių arba autoritetinių
duomenų paieškai palengvinti.
</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Dodatkowy punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Punkt dostępu, który może być
stosowany dodatkowo obok podstawowego punktu dostępu w celu ułatwienia wyszukiwania danych bibliograficznych lub wzorcowych.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso adicional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso que pode ser usado para além dos pontos de acesso essenciais para melhorar a pesquisa de registos bibliográficos ou de autoridade.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Дополнительная точка доступа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">точка доступа, которая может быть использована в дополнение к обязательным точкам доступа, чтобы облегчить поиск  библиографических или авторитетных данных.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Dodatna pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pristupna tačka koja može da se koristi uz glavne pristupne tačke kako bi se poboljšalo pretraživabhe bibliografskih ili normativnih podataka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Doplnkový selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Selekčný údaj, ktorý je možné použiť na doplnenie základných selekčných údajov na uľahčenie vyhľadávania bibliografických alebo autoritatívnych údajov.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Dodatna vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Vstopna točka, ki jo lahko uporabimo poleg osnovne vstopne točke za učinkovitejše iskanje bibliografskih in normativnih podatkov.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso adicional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un punto de acceso que se puede utilizar, además de los puntos de acceso esenciales, para mejorar la recuperación de datos bibliográficos o de autoridad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Ytterligare sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En sökingång som kan användas utöver de grundläggande sökingångarna för att förbättra återvinningen av bibliografisk data och auktoritetsdata.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงอื่น ๆ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงหนึ่งที่สามารถนำมาใช้นอกเหนือจากจุดเข้าถึงที่จำเป็น 
เพื่อเพิ่มความสามารถในการค้นคืนรายการบรรณานุกรมและรายการควบคุม
</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập bổ sung</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một điểm truy cập có thể dùng bổ sung cho những điểm truy cập cần thiết để tăng số điểm truy cập đến dữ liệu thư mục hay dữ liệu tác giả.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#EssentialAccessPoint"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Agent  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Agent" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4677"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A person (author, publisher, sculptor, editor, director, composer, etc.) or a group (family, organization, corporation, library, orchestra, country, federation, etc.) or an automaton (weather recording device, software translation program, etc.) that has a role in the lifecycle of a resource.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Agjent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Person (autor, botues, skulptor, redaktor, drejtues, kompozitor, etj.) ose grup (familje, organizatë, korporatë, bibliotekë, orkestër, krahinë, federatë etj.) ose robot (pajisje për regjistrimin e kushteve të motit, program software për përkthim automatik etj.) që luan rol në ekzistencën e një burimi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">العامل</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">) شخص (مؤلف، ناشر، نحات، محرر، مخرج، ملحن، الخ) أو مجموعة (عائلة، منظمة، شركة، مكتبة، أوركسترا، قطر، اتحاد، الخ) أو تقنية (جهاز تسجيل المناخ، برنامج ترجمة، الخ) له دور في دورة حياة المصدر.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Агент</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Лице (автор, издател, скулптор, редактор, режисьор, композитор и т.н.), група (фамилия, организация, корпорация, библиотека, оркестър, страна,  федерация и т.н.) или автоматично устройство (уред за регистриране на климатични промени, компютърна програма за автоматичен превод и т.н.), които имат определена роля за жизнения цикъл на ресурс. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Persona (autor, editor, escultor, editor literari, director, compositor, etc.) o grup (família, organització, societat, biblioteca, orquestra, país, federació, etc.) o autòmat (dispositiu enregistrador de dades meteorològiques, programari de traducció, etc.) que te un paper en el cicle de vida d’un recurs.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">代理</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">在资源的生命周期中发挥某种作用的一个人（著者、出版者、雕塑家、编者、导演、作曲家等）、一群人（家族、组织、社团、图书馆、乐队、国家、联合会等）或一个自动装置（气象记录仪、软件翻译程序等）。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Posrednik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Osoba (autor, nakladnik, kipar, urednik, režiser, kompozitor itd.) ili skupina (obitelj, ustanova, korporacija, knjižnica, orkestar, država, federacija itd.) ili stroj (uređaj za snimanje, program za prevođenje softvera itd.) koji imaju neku ulogu u životnom ciklusu jedinice.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Osoba (autor, nakladatel, sochař, editor, režisér, skladatel atd.) či skupina (rodina, organizace, korporace, knihovna, orchestr, stát, federace atd.) či automat (zařízení zaznamenávající počasí, překladač atd.), které mají roli v životním cyklu zdroje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Agentti</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Henkilö (kirjoittaja, julkaisija, kuvanveistäjä, toimittaja, elokuvan ohjaaja, säveltäjä jne.) tai ryhmä (perhe/suku, organisaatio, yhtiö, kirjasto, orkesteri, maa, liittovaltio jne.) tai robotti (säätä rekisteröivä laite, ohjelmiston käännösohjelma jne.), jolla on oma tehtävä resurssin elinkaaressa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Une personne (auteur, éditeur commercial, sculpteur, éditeur scientifique, directeur, compositeur, etc.) ou un groupe (famille, organisme, société, bibliothèque, orchestre, pays, fédération, etc.) ou un automate (dispositif enregistreur de mesures météorologiques, logiciel de traduction, etc.) qui joue un rôle dans le cycle de vie d’une ressource.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Person (Autor, Verleger, Bildhauer, Herausgeber, Regisseur. Komponist etc.) oder eine Gruppe (Familie, Organisation, Firma, Bibliothek, Orchester, Land, Vereinigung etc.) oder ein Automat (Wetterstation, Softwareübersetzungsprogramm etc.), die eine Rolle im Lebenszyklus einer Ressource spielt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Agente</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Persona (autore, editore, scultore, curatore, direttore, compositore, ecc.), o gruppo (famiglia, organizzazione, società, biblioteca, orchestra, paese, federazione, ecc.) o robot (stazione per il rilevamento delle condizioni atmosferiche, programma software di traduzione automatica, ecc.) che abbia un ruolo nel ciclo produttivo di una risorsa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">行為主体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">ある資料のライフサイクルにおいて、何らかの役割を果たす個人（著者、出版者、彫刻家、編者、監督、作曲家等）、集団（家族、組織、会社、図書館、交響楽団、国家、連邦等）または自動的手段（気象記録装置、翻訳ソフトウェア等）。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">책임주체</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">자원의 생명주기에서 역할을 지닌 개인(저자, 발행자, 조각가, 편자, 감독, 작곡가 등)이나 집단(가족, 조직, 회사, 도서관, 관현악단, 국가, 연맹 등), 자동장치(기상기록장치, 번역프로그램 소프트웨어 등)</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Aģents</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Persona (autors, izdevējs, tēlnieks, redaktors, režisors, komponists u.tml.) vai grupa (dzimta, organizācija, korporācija, bibliotēka, orķestris, valsts, federācija u.tml.), vai automatizēta sistēma (meteoroloģiskā ieraksta ierīce, konvertēšanas programmatūra u.tml.), kam ir nozīme resursa tapšanas un pastāvēšanas laikā.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Veiksnys</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Asmuo (autorius, leidėjas, skulptorius, redaktorius, režisierius, kompozitorius ir
t. t.) arba grupė (giminė, organizacija, korporacija, biblioteka, orkestras, šalis, federacija ir
t. t.), arba automatas (orus fiksuojantis prietaisas, vertimo programa ir t. t.), kurie turi reikšmę
ištekliaus gyvavimo ciklui.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Osoba (autor, wydawca, rzeźbiarz, redaktor, reżyser, kompozytor itd.) lub grupa (rodzina, organizacja, przedsiębiorstwo, biblioteka, orkiestra, kraj, federacja itd.) lub automat (urządzenie zapisujące warunki pogody, oprogramowanie do tłumaczenia itd.), które biorą udział w cyklu życia dokumentu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Agente</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Pessoa (autor, editor, escultor, editor literário, diretor, compositor, etc.) ou um grupo (família, organização, empresa, biblioteca, orquestra, país, federação, etc.) ou um recurso automático (por exemplo, um mecanismo de registo de condições atmosféricas, uma aplicação informática de tradução, etc.) que tem uma função no ciclo de vida de um recurso.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Агент</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Лицо (автор, издатель, скульптор, редактор, режиссер, композитор и др.),  или группа (род, организация, корпорация, библиотека, оркестр, страна, федерация и т.п.), или автомат (устройство, регистрирующее погоду, электронная программа-переводчик и т. п.), которые играют определенную роль в жизненном цикле ресурса.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Posrednik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Osoba (autor, izdavač, vajar, urednik, režiser, kompozitor i tako dalje) ili grupa (porodica, ustanova, korporacija, biblioteka, orkestar, država, federacija i tako dalje) ili uređaj (uređaj za snimanje, program za prevođenje softvera i tako dalje) koji imaju neku ulogu u životnom ciklusu izvora.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Osoba (autor, vydavateľ, sochár, editor, režisér, skladateľ atď.) alebo skupina (rodina, organizácia, korporácia, knižnica, orchester, štát, federácia atď.) alebo automat (zariadenie zaznamenávajúce počasie, prekladač atď.), ktoré majú úlohu v životnom cykle zdroja. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Dejavnik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oseba (avtor, založnik, kipar, izdajatelj, režiser, skladatelj itn.) ali skupina (rodbina, organizacija, korporacija, knjižnica, orkester, dežela, federacija itn.) ali avtomatska naprava (vremenska hišica, računalniški program za prevajanje itn.), ki  ima v življenju vira neko vlogo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Agente</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una persona (autor, editor, escultor, editor literario, director, compositor, etc.) o un grupo (familia, organización, entidad corporativa, biblioteca, orquesta, país, federación, etc.) o autómata (mecanismo de recogida de datos meteorológicos, programas software de traducción, etc.) que ha desempeñado un papel en el ciclo vital de un recurso.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Agent</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En person (författare, förläggare, skulptör, utgivare, regissör, kompositör etc.) eller en grupp (familj, organisation, företag, bibliotek, orkester, land, federation etc.) eller en automatisk agent (automatisk väderstation, översättningsprogram etc.) som haft en roll i resursens livscykel.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ตัวแทน</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">บุคคล (เช่น ผู้แต่ง, ผู้พิมพ์, ผู้ปั้น, บรรณาธิการ, ผู้กำกับ, ผู้ควบคุม เป็นต้น) หรือกลุ่มบุคคล (เช่น ครอบครัว, นิติบุคคล, บริษัท, ห้องสมุด, วงดนตรี, ประเทศ, สหภาพเป็นต้น) หรือเครื่องมืออัตโนมัติ (เช่น อุปกรณ์พยากรณ์อากาศ, โปรแกรมแปลซอฟท์แวร์ เป็นต้น) ที่มีบทบาทในวัฏจักรทรัพยากรสารสนเทศ</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Chủ thể</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một người (tác giả, nhà xuất bản, nhà điêu khắc, nhà biên tập, giám đốc, soạn giả,...) hoặc một nhóm (gia đình, tổ chức, tập đoàn, thư viện, ban nhạc, đất nước, liên đoàn,...) hoặc máy móc, thiết bị (thiết bị đo thời tiết, chương trình phần mềm dịch,...) có vai trò trong vòng đời của nguồn lực.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Creator"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Attribute  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Attribute" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4678"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Attribute</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Characteristic of an entity.  An attribute can be inherent in an entity or externally imputed.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Karakteristikë e një entiteti. Atributi mund të jetë i brendaqënësishëm në një entitet ose i jashtëm.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الحقل</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">خاصية من الكيان. قد يكون الحقل من صلب الكيان أو منسوب خارجيا.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Атрибут</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Характеристика на обект. Атрибутът може да бъде вътрешно присъщ на обекта или заимстван.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Característica d’una entitat. Un atribut pot ser inherent a una entitat o pot ser assignat externament.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">属性</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一个实体的特征。属性可以是实体内在的，或由外部输入的。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Svojstvo entiteta. Atribut može biti urođen u entitetu ili mu može biti izvana nametnut.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Charakteristika entity. Atribut může být součástí entity či připisovaný entitě zvnějšku.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Attribuutti</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Entiteetin ominaisuus. Attribuutti voi olla olennainen osa entiteettiä tai se voi olla ulkoinen lisäys.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Attribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Caractéristique d’une entité. Un attribut peut être inhérent à une entité ou lui être affecté.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Merkmal</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Charakteristikum einer Entität. Ein Merkmal kann einer Entität innewohnen oder ihr zugeschrieben werden.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Attributo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Caratteristica di un’entità. Un attributo può essere intrinseco all’entità o assegnato esternamente.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">属性</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">実体の特性。属性には、実体に固有の属性と外的に付与される属性がある。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">속성</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체의 특성. 속성은 어떤 개체에 내재된 고유한 것일 수 있고, 외부에 있는 것을 따른 것일 수 있다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Atribūts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Raksturīga entītijas iezīme. Atribūts var būt entītijai sākotnēji piemītošs vai ārēju apstākļu radīts.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Atributas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Entiteto charakteristika. Atributas gali būti neatskiriama entiteto dalis arba priskiriama jam išoriškai.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Atrybut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Cecha jednostki. Atrybut może być właściwy jednostce lub nadany.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Atributo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Característica de uma entidade. Um atributo pode ser intrínseco a uma entidade ou ser-lhe externamente imputado.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Атрибут </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Характеристика объекта. Атрибут может быть неотъемлемой частью объекта, а может быть заимствован извне.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Karakteristika entiteta; atribut može da bude svojstven samo entitetu ili može da mu bude nametnut spolja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Atribút</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Charakteristika entity. Atribút môže byť súčasťou entity alebo pripisovaný entite zvonka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Atribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Lastnost entitete. Atribut je lahko lasten sami entiteti ali pa izvira od zunaj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Atributo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La característica de una entidad; un atributo puede ser inherente a una entidad o atribuido externamente.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Attribut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Entitetens egenskaper. Attributen kan vara en del av entiteten eller ha tilldelats denna.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">แอททริบิวท์</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">คุณลักษณะของเอนทิตี แอททริบิวท์สามารถสืบทอดกันภายในเอนทิตีหรือสร้าง ขึ้นจากภายนอกได้</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Thuộc tính</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Đặc điểm của một thực thể. Một thuộc tính có thể là đặc tính vốn có của thực thế hay là yếu tố ngoại lai.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Authority record  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorityRecord" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4679"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Authority record</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A set of data elements that identifies an entity and can be used to facilitate access to the authorized access point for that entity or the display of any access point for the entity.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Regjistrim termi të njësuar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Grup me elemente të dhënash që identifikojnë një entitet dhe mund të përdoren për të lehtësuar akcesin në pikën hyrëse të autorizuar (të njësuar) për atë entitet ose shfaqjen e ndonjë pikë hyrëse për entitetin.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">التسجيلة الاستنادية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">مجموعة من عناصر البيانات تحدد كيان ما، ويمكن أن تستخدم لتسهيل الوصول لنقطة الوصول المقننة لهذا الكيان أو لعرض أي نقطة وصول للكيان.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Контролен запис</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Съвкупност от елементи от данни, която идентифицира определен обект и може да бъде използвана за улесняване на достъпа до установената точка за достъп до този обект или за визуализация на всяка точка за достъп до нея.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Registre d’autoritat</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Conjunt d’elements de dades que identifica una entitat i que es pot utilitzar per facilitar l’accés al punt d’accés autoritzat d’aquesta entitat o per visualitzar qualsevol punt d’accés assignat a l’entitat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">规范记录</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">识别某一实体，并可为存取该实体的规范检索点或显示该实体的任何检索点提供便利的一组数据单元。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Pregledni zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Skup podatkovnih elemenata koji identificiraju entitet i koji se mogu upotrijebiti za olakšavanje pristupa usvojenoj pristupnici za taj entitet ili za prikaz bilo koje pristupnice za taj entitet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Autoritní záznam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Soubor datových prvků, které identifikují entitu a mohou být použity k usnadnění přístupu k autorizovanému selekčnímu údaji či zobrazení selekčního údaje pro entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Auktoriteettitietue</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Tietoelementtien joukko, joka identifioi entiteetin ja joka helpottaa entiteetin auktorisoidun hakutiedon tai muun sitä koskevan hakutiedon löytämistä.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Notice d’autorité</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Ensemble des éléments de données qui identifie une entité et qui peut être utilisé afin de faciliter l’accès au point d’accès autorisé pour cette entité ou l’affichage de tout point d’accès établi pour cette entité.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Normdatensatz</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Datensatz, der eine Entität identifiziert und dafür genutzt werden kann, den Zugang zur Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs oder die Anzeige eines anderen Sucheinstiegs dieser Entität zu ermöglichen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Insieme di dati che identifica un’entità e che può essere usata per facilitare l’accesso al punto di accesso autorizzato per quell’entità o per la visualizzazione di qualsiasi punto di accesso per l’entità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Registrazione di autorità</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">典拠レコード</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">実体を識別し、その実体に対する典拠形アクセスポイントへのアクセスを、またはその実体に対するどのアクセスポイントの表示をも容易にするために用いることができるデータ要素の一群</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">전거레코드</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체를 식별하고, 해당 개체의 전거형 접근점 혹은 해당 개체의 모든 접근점 표시에 접근을 촉진하기 위하여 사용될 수 있는 데이터 요소 집합</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Autoritatīvais ieraksts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Datu elementu kopums, kas identificē entītiju, un kuru var izmantot piekļuves atvieglošanai vai jebkura šīs entītijas piekļuves punkta parādīšanai ekrānā.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Autoritetinis įrašas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Duomenų elementų rinkinys, kuris identifikuoja entitetą ir gali būti vartojamas palengvinti prieigą prie aprobuoto kreipties elemento šiam entitetui arba bet kurio kreipties elemento entitetui išvedimą.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Rekord wzorcowy</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Zestaw elementów danych, który identyfikuje jednostkę i może być stosowany dla ułatwienia dostępu do ujednoliconego punktu dostępu do danej jednostki lub wyświetlenia jakiegokolwiek punktu dostępu do tej jednostki.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Registo de autoridade</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Conjunto de elementos de dados que identifica uma entidade e pode ser usado para facilitar o acesso ao ponto de acesso autorizado para essa entidade ou a para disponibilizar quaisquer outros pontos de acesso para a entidade.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Авторитетная запись </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Совокупность элементов данных, которая идентифицирует объект  и может использоваться, чтобы облегчить доступ к авторитетной точке доступа для этого объекта или  вывод любой точки доступа для объекта.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Normativni zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Skup elemenata podataka koji identifikuju entitet i koji mogu da se koriste da se olakša pristup normiranoj pristupnoj tački tog entiteta ili prikaz bilo koje pristupne tačke tog entiteta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Autoritatívny záznam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Súbor údajových prvkov, ktoré identifikujú entitu a môžu byť použité na uľahčenie prístupu k autorizovanému selekčnému údaju alebo na zobrazenie selekčného údaja pre entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Normativni zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Zbir podatkov, ki identificirajo entiteto in omogočajo dostop do normativne vstopne točke ali prikaz katerekoli vstopne točke.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Registro de autoridad</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un conjunto de datos que identifica a una entidad y que puede ser utilizado para facilitar el acceso a  los puntos de acceso autorizados para la entidad o para la visualización de cualquiera de los puntos de acceso para la entidad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Auktoritetspost</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En uppsättning dataelement som identifierar en entitet och kan användas för att underlätta tillgången till dess auktoriserade sökingång eller visningen av alla sökingångar för entiteten.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รายการควบคุม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชุดขององค์ประกอบของข้อมูลที่ระบุถึงเอนทิตี ซึ่งสามารถเอื้อประโยชน์ต่อ การเข้าถึงจุดเข้าถึงข้อมูลที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้ของเอนทิตี หรือการจัดแสดงจุดเข้าถึงข้อมูลใด ๆ ของเอนทิตีได้</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Hồ sơ tiêu đề chuẩn</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tập hợp các nhân tố dữ liệu xác định một thực thể hay được sử dụng để cung cấp điểm truy cập được cho phép đến một thực thể hay sự trình bày cho bất kể điểm truy cập nào của thực thể.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Authorized access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4680"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Authorized access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The preferred controlled access point for an entity, established and constructed according to rules or standards.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse e autorizuar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pika hyrëse e kontrolluar e preferuar për një entitet, e vendosur dhe e ndërtuar sipas rregullave ose standardeve.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول المقننة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول المفضلة المضبوطة للكيان، أنشئت وبنيت طبقا لقواعد ومعايير.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Установена точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Предпочетената контролирана точка за достъп за определен обект, утвърдена и съставена в съответствие с правила или стандарти.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés autoritzat</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés controlat preferit d’una entitat, establert i elaborat segons unes regles o estàndards.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">规范检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">按规则或标准确立与构建的一个实体的首选受控检索点。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Usvojena pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Izabrana nadzirana pristupnica za entitet uspostavljena i izrađena prema pravilima ili standardima.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Autorizovaný selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Preferovaný řízený selekční údaj pro entitu, stanovený a vytvořený podle pravidel či standardů.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Auktorisoitu hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Entiteetin ensisijainen kontrolloitu hakutieto, joka on laadittu ja muodostettu sääntöjen ja standardien mukaisesti.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès autorisé</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès contrôlé privilégié pour une entité, établi et construit selon des règles ou des normes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der bevorzugte normierte Sucheinstieg für eine Entität, der nach gültigen Regeln und Standards gebildet wurde.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso autorizzato</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso controllato preferito per una entità, stabilito e costruito secondo regole o standard.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">典拠形アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">規則または基準に従って確立され作成される、実体に対する優先的な統制形アクセスポイント</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">전거형 접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">규칙이나 표준에 따라 선정되고 구축된 개체에 대한 채택된 제어형 접근점</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Autorizētais piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Ieteicamais kontrolētais entītijas piekļuves punkts, kas veidots un apstiprināts atbilstoši noteikumiem vai standartiem.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Aprobuotas kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Prioritetinis kontroliuojamas kreipties elementas entitetui, nustatytas ir sudarytas vadovaujantis taisyklėmis arba standartais.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Ujednolicony punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Przyjęty kontrolowany punkt
dostępu do jednostki, ustalony i sformułowany zgodnie z zasadami lub standardami.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso autorizado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso controlado preferido para uma entidade, estabelecido e formulado de acordo com regras e normas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Авторитетная точка доступа </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Предпочтительная контролируемая точка доступа к объекту, установленная и сформированная в соответствии   с правилами или стандартами</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Normirana pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Preferentna kontrolisana pristupna tačka entiteta ustanovljena i formirana prema pravilima ili standardima.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Autorizovaný selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Preferovaný riadený selekčný údaj pre entitu, stanovený a vytvorený podľa pravidiel alebo štandardov.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Normativna vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Izbrana kontrolirana vstopna točka do entitete, določena in oblikovana v skladu s pravili in standardi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso autorizado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">El punto de acceso controlado preferido para una entidad, establecido y construido de acuerdo a unas reglas o normas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Auktoriserad sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Den föredragna kontrollerade sökingången för en entitet, fastställd och utformad enligt gällande regler eller standarder.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงควบคุมสำหรับเอนทิตีที่ให้ความสำคัญและ ถูกสร้างขึ้นตามกฎเกณฑ์และมาตรฐาน</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập được phép</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập có kiểm soát và được ưu tiên đến một thực thể, được hình thành và xây dựng dựa trên qui tắc và tiêu chuẩn.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Normalized access point</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse e standardizuar</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول المطبعة</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="bg">Нормализирана точка за достъп</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés normalitzat</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="zh">标准化检索点</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="hr">Normalizirana pristupnica</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="cs">Normalizovaný selekční údaj</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fi">Normalisoitu hakutieto</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès normalisé</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="de">Normalisierter Sucheinstieg</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso normalizzato</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ja">統一形アクセスポイント</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ko">정규화된 접근점</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="lt">Sunormintas kreipties elementas</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="pl">Znormalizowany punkt dostępu</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso normalizado</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ru">Нормализованная точка доступа</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="sr">Propisana pristupna tačka</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="sk">Normalizovaný selekčný údaj</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="sl">Normirana vstopna točka</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso normalizado</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="sv">Normaliserad sökingång</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้เป็นบรรทัดฐาน</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập được bình thường hóa</skos:altLabel>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#PreferredName"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Authorized form of name  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4681"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Authorized form of name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The form of name chosen as the authorized access point for an entity.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Formë e autorizuar e emrit</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Forma e emrit e zgjedhur si pikë hyrëse e autorizuar (e njësuar) për një entitet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الشكل المقنن للاسم</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هو شكل الاسم الذي تم اختياره كنقطة وصول مقننة للكيان. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Установена форма на име (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Формата на името (наименованието), избрана за установена точка за достъп за определен обект.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Forma autoritzada del nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Forma del nom triada com a punt d’accés autoritzat d’una entitat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">名称的规范形式</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">选为实体规范检索点的名称形式。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Usvojeni oblik imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Oblik imena odabran za usvojenu pristupnicu entitetu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Autorizovaná forma jména</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Forma jména zvolená za autorizovaný selekční údaj pro entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Auktorisoitu nimimuoto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Nimimuoto, joka on valittu entiteetin auktorisoiduksi hakutiedoksi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Forme autorisée d’un nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">La forme du nom choisie comme point d’accès autorisé pour une entité. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Ansetzungsform des Namens</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Die Namensform, die als Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs für eine Entität gewählt wird.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Forma autorizzata del nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Forma del nome scelta come punto di accesso autorizzato per una entità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">名称の典拠形</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">実体に対する典拠形アクセスポイントとして選定された名称の形。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">전거형 이름</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체의 전거형 접근점으로 선정된 이름의 형식</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Personvārda/nosaukuma autorizētā forma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Entītijas autorizētā piekļuves punkta (personvārda/nosaukuma) forma.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Aprobuota vardo forma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vardo forma, pasirinkta kaip aprobuotas kreipties elementas entitetui.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Ujednolicona forma nazwy</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Forma nazwy wybrana jako
ujednolicony punkt dostępu do jednostki.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Forma autorizada de nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Forma de nome escolhida como ponto de acesso autorizado para uma entidade.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Авторитетная форма имени (наименования)  </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Форма имени (наименования), выбранная в качестве авторитетной точки доступа для объекта.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Usvojeni oblik imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Oblik imena koji je izabran kao normirana pristupna tačka entiteta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Autorizovaná forma mena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Forma mena zvolená za autorizovaný selekčný údaj pre entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Normativna oblika imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oblika imena, ki jo izberemo kot normativno vstopno točko do entitete.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Forma autorizada del nombre</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La forma del nombre elegida como punto de acceso autorizado para la entidad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Auktoriserad namnform</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Den namnform som valts som auktoriserad sökingång för entiteten.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รูปแบบชื่อที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">รูปแบบชื่อที่ถูกเลือกให้เป็นจุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้ ใช้ได้ของเอนทิตี</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Hình thức được phép của tên</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Hình thức của tên được lựa chọn là điểm truy cập được phép đến một thực thể.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#PreferredName"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ConventionalName"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Bibliographic description  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicDescription" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4682"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bibliographic description</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A set of bibliographic data identifying a bibliographic resource.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Përshkrim bibliografik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Grup të dhënash bibliografike që identifikojnë një burim bibliografik.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الوصف الببليوغرافي</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">مجموعة من البيانات الببليوغرافية تحدد مصدر ببليوغرافي.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Библиографско описание</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Съвкупност от библиографски данни, които идентифицират библиографските ресурс.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Descripció bibliogràfica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Conjunt de dades bibliogràfiques que identifica un recurs bibliogràfic.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">书目著录</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">识别某一书目资源的一组书目数据。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Bibliografski opis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Skup bibliografskih podataka koji identificiraju bibliografsku jedinicu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Bibliografický popis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Soubor bibliografických údajů identifikujících bibliografický zdroj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Bibliografinen kuvailu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Joukko bibliografisia tietoja, joiden avulla bibliografinen resurssi tunnistetaan.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Description bibliographique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Ensemble de données bibliographiques qui identifie une ressource bibliographique.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bibliografische Beschreibung</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Set bibliografischer Daten, das eine bibliografische Ressource identifiziert.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Descrizione bibliografica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Insieme di dati bibliografici che identificano una risorsa bibliografica.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">書誌記述</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">ある書誌的資源を識別する一群の書誌データ。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">서지기술</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지자원을 식별하는 일련의 서지데이터 [출처: ISBD의 것을 수정]</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfiskais apraksts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfisko datu kopums bibliogrāfiskā resursa identificēšanai.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Bibliografinis aprašas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Bibliografinių duomenų, identifikuojančių
bibliografinį išteklių, rinkinys.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Opis bibliograficzny</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Zbiór danych bibliograficznych
identyfikujących zasób bibliograficzny.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Descrição bibliográfica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Conjunto de dados bibliográficos que identificam um recurso bibliográfico.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Библиографическое описание </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Совокупность библиографических данных, идентифицирующих библиографический ресурс.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Bibliografski opis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Skup bibliografskih podataka koji identifikuju bibliografski izvor.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Bibliografický popis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Súbor bibliografických údajov identifikujúcich bibliografický zdroj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bibliografski opis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Zbir bibliografskih podatkov, ki identificirajo bibliografski vir.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Descripción bibliográfica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Conjunto de información bibliográfica que identifica un recurso bibliográfico.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bibliografisk beskrivning</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En uppsättning bibliografiska data som identifierar en bibliografisk resurs.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รายละเอียดทางบรรณานุกรม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชุดข้อมูลบรรณานุกรมที่ระบุทรัพยากรทาง บรรณานุกรม</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Mô tả thư mục</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tập hợp dữ liệu thư mục xác định nguồn thư mục.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#DescriptiveCataloguing"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Bibliographic record  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicRecord" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4683"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bibliographic record</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A set of data elements that describes and provides access to a bibliographic resource and identifies related works and expressions.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Regjistrim bibliografik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Grup me elemente të dhënash që përshkruajnë dhe sigurojnë akces në një burim bibliografik, dhe identifikojnë veprat dhe shprehjet që lidhen me të.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">التسجيلة الببليوغرافية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">مجموعة من عناصر البيانات التي تصف وتتيح الوصول إلى المصدر الببليوغرافي وتحدد الأعمال والتعبيرات ذات العلاقة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Библиографски запис</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Съвкупността от елементи от данни, която описва и осигурява достъп до библиографски ресурс и идентифицира свързани произведения и форми на проявление.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Registre bibliogràfic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Conjunt d’elements de dades que descriu i proporciona accés a un recurs bibliogràfic i identifica les obres i expressions relacionades.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">书目记录</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">描述和检索某一书目资源以及识别相关作品和内容表达的一组数据单元。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Bibliografski zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Skup podatkovnih elemenata koji opisuju i osiguravaju pristup bibliografskoj jedinici i identificiraju srodna djela i izraze.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Bibliografický záznam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Soubor datových prvků, který popisuje bibliografický zdroj, poskytuje k němu přístup a identifikuje související díla a vyjádření.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Bibliografinen tietue</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Joukko tietoelementtejä, joiden avulla bibliografinen resurssi kuvaillaan ja löydetään sekä resurssiin liittyvät teokset ja ekspressiot tunnistetaan.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Notice bibliographique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Ensemble des éléments de données qui décrit et donne accès à une ressource bibliographique, et qui identifie les œuvres et les expressions associées.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bibliografischer Datensatz</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Set von Datenelementen, das eine bibliografische Ressource beschreibt und den Zugriff darauf bietet, sowie mit dieser verwandte Werke und Expressionen identifiziert.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Registrazione bibliografica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Insieme di dati che descrive e fornisce accesso a una risorsa bibliografica e identifica opere ed espressioni ad essa correlate.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">書誌レコード</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">書誌的資源の記述および書誌的資源へのアクセス提供を行い、また関連する著作および表現形を識別する一群のデータ要素。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">서지레코드</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지 자원을 기술하고 접근하기 위한 데이터 요소의 집합으로서 관련 저작과 표현형을 식별한다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfiskais ieraksts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Datu elementu kopums, kas apraksta bibliogrāfisko resursu un nodrošina tam piekļuvi, kā arī identificē radniecīgos darbus un izteiksmes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Bibliografinis įrašas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Duomenų elementų rinkinys, kuris aprašo bibliografinį išteklių, suteikia prieigą prie jo ir identifikuoja susijusius kūrinius ir išraiškas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Rekord bibliograficzny</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Zbiór elementów danych, który opisuje I zapewnia dostęp do zasobu bibliograficznego, oraz identyfikuje związane z nim dzieła i realizacje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Registo bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Conjunto de elementos de dados que descreve e dá acesso a um recurso bibliográfico e identifica obras e expressões relacionadas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Библиографическая запись</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Совокупность элементов данных для описания и обеспечения доступа к библиографическому ресурсу и идентификации связанных произведений и выражений.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Bibliografski zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Skup elemenata podataka koji opisuju i obezbeđuju pristup bibliografskom izvoru i identifikuju srodna dela i izraze.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Bibliografický záznam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Súbor údajových prvkov, ktorý popisuje bibliografický zdroj, poskytuje k nemu prístup a identifikuje súvisiace diela a vyjadrenia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bibliografski zapis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Zbir podatkov, ki opisujejo bibliografski vir in omogočajo dostop do njega ter identificirajo sorodna dela in izrazne oblike.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Registro bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un conjunto de elementos de información que describe y proporciona acceso a un recurso bibliográfico e identifica las obras relacionadas y las expresiones.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bibliografisk post</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En uppsättning dataelement som beskriver och ger tillgång till en bibliografisk resurs samt identifierar relaterade verk och uttryck.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รายการบรรณานุกรม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชุดองค์ประกอบข้อมูลที่บรรยายและเชื่อมโยงการเข้าถึงทรัพยากรทางบรรณานุกรมและระบุงานและรูปแบบการนำเสนอที่เกี่ยวข้อง</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Biểu ghi thư mục</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tập hợp các yếu tố dữ liệu mô tả và cung cấp truy cập tới nguồn thư mục và xác định tác phẩm hay biểu ngữ.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Bibliographic resource  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicResource" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4684"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bibliographic resource</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An entity within the realm of library and similar collections consisting of the products of intellectual or artistic endeavour.  Bibliographic resources in the FRBR model are the Group 1 entities: work, expression, manifestation, and item.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Burim bibliografik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Entitet në sferën bibliotekare ose në koleksione të ngjashme që është produkt i përpjekjeve intelektuale ose artistike. Burimet bibliografike janë entitetet e Grupit 1 në modelin FRBR: vepra, shprehja, manifestimi dhe njësia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">المصدر الببليوغرافي</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هو كيان متداخل ضمن عالم المكتبات والمجموعات المماثلة، ويشمل منتجات الإبداعات الفكرية والفنية. والمصادر الببليوغرافية في نموذج FRBR هي كيانات المجموعة الأولى: العمل، التعبير، الإظهار والوعاء.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Библиографски ресурс</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Обект от областта на библиотечните и подобните на тях колекции, която се състои от продуктите на интелектуално или художествено творчество. Във FRBR библиографските ресурси са обектите от Група 1: произведение, форма на проявление, форма на физическо представяне и физическа единица.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Recurs bibliogràfic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Entitat de l’àmbit de les biblioteques i col•leccions similars formada per productes de l’activitat intel•lectual o artística. En el model FRBR, els recursos bibliogràfics són les entitats del Grup 1: obra, expressió, manifestació i ítem.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">书目资源</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">在图书馆以及由知识或艺术创作的产品所组成的类似收藏领域中的一个实体。在FRBR模型中的书目资源是第1组实体：作品、内容表达、载体表现和单件。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Bibliografska jedinica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Entitet unutar područja knjižničnih i sličnih zbirki koje sadrže proizvode intelektualnog ili umjetničkog dostignuća. Bibliografsku jedinicu u modelu FRBR čine entiteti prve skupine: djelo, izraz, pojavni oblik i jedinica građe.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Bibliografický zdroj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Entita v rámci sféry knihovních a podobných sbírek sestávající z výsledků intelektuálního či uměleckého úsilí. Bibliografické zdroje v modelu FRBR jsou entity Skupiny 1: dílo, vyjádření, provedení a jednotka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Bibliografinen resurssi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Kirjasto-ja vastaaviin muihin kokoelmiin kuuluva entiteetti, joka on tiedollisen tai taiteellisen toiminnan tulos. FRBR-mallissa bibliografisia resursseja ovat entiteetit: teos, ekspressio, manifestaatio ja kappale.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Ressource bibliographique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Entité constituée par les produits d’une entreprise intellectuelle ou artistique, aussi bien dans le domaine des bibliothèques que dans celui de collections similaires. Dans le modèle FRBR, les ressources bibliographiques sont les entités du Groupe 1 : œuvre, expression, manifestation, et item.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bibliografische Ressource</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Entität im Bereich von Bibliotheksbeständen und ähnlichen Sammlungen, die aus den Produkten von intellektuellen oder künstlerischen Bemühungen besteht. Bibliografische Ressourcen im FRBR-Modell sind die Entitäten der Gruppe 1: Werk, Expression, Manifestation und Exemplar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Risorsa bibliografica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Un’entità nell’ambito della biblioteca e di raccolte analoghe che consiste di prodotti dell’attività intellettuale o artistica. Nel modello FRBR le risorse bibliografiche sono le entità del I Gruppo: opera, espressione, manifestazione ed esemplare.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">書誌的資源</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">知的・芸術的活動の成果から成る、図書館領域および類似領域のコレクションの中の実体。FRBRモデルにおける書誌的資源は、グループ1の実体である著作、表現形、体現形および個別資料である。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">서지자원</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">지적 혹은 예술적 노력의 산물로 구성된 도서관 및 유사한 집서에서의 개체. FRBR 모형에서 서지자원은 그룹1의 개체로 저작, 표현형, 구현형, 개별자료이다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfiskais resurss</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Bibliotēku vai tamlīdzīgos krājumos esoša entītija, kas ietver intelektuāla vai mākslinieciska darba augļus. Atbilstoši FRBR modelim 1. grupas entītijas ir: darbs, izteiksme, manifestācija un vienība.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Bibliografinis išteklius</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Bibliotekų ir panašių rinkinių entitetas, susidedantis iš intelektinės ar meninės kūrybos produktų. Bibliografiniai ištekliai FRBR modelyje yra 1-osios grupės entitetai: kūrinys, išraiška, apraiška ir vienetas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Zasób bibliograficzny</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Jednostka w sferze zbiorów biblioteki lub podobnych zbiorów, składających się z wytworów działalności intelektualnej lub artystycznej. Zasoby bibliograficzne w modelu FRBR stanowią grupę 1 jednostek: dzieło, realizacja, materializacja i egzemplarz.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Recurso bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Entidade do âmbito das coleções bibliográficas e similares consistindo em produtos de caráter intelectual ou artístico. Os recursos bibliográficos constituem, no modelo FRBR, as entidades do grupo 1: obra, expressão, manifestação e item.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Библиографический ресурс </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Объект в сфере библиотечных или подобных коллекций, состоящий из продукта интеллектуального или художественного творчества. Библиографические ресурсы в модели FRBR – это объекты 1-й группы: произведение, выражение, воплощение и физическая единица.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Bibliografski izvor</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Entitet koji poseduje biblioteka i slične kolekcije, i koji je proizvod intelektualnog ili umetničkog rada.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Bibliografický zdroj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Entita v rámci sféry knižničných a podobných zbierok
pozostávajúca z výsledkov intelektuálneho alebo umeleckého úsilia. Bibliografické zdroje v modeli FRBR sú entity Skupiny 1: dielo, vyjadrenie, prezentácia a jednotka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bibliografski vir</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Entiteta znotraj knjižnice ali podobne zbirke del, ki je rezultat intelektualnih ali umetniških prizadevanj. Bibliografski viri v okviru modela FRBR so entitete 1. skupine: delo, izrazna oblika, pojavna oblika in enota.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Recurso bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una entidad, dentro del ámbito de bibliotecas o colecciones similares,  que consta del producto del esfuerzo intelectual o artístico.  En el modelo FRBR, los recursos bibliográficos son las entidades del Grupo 1:obra, expresión, manifestación y ejemplar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bibliografisk resurs</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En entitet inom biblioteksvärlden och liknande samlingar. Bibliografiska resurser består av produkter av intellektuellt eller konstnärligt skapande. I FRBR-modellen utgör dessa resurser entiteterna i grupp 1: verk, uttryck, manifestation och exemplar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ทรัพยากรทางบรรณานุกรม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">เอนทิตีที่อยู่ภายในขอบเขตของห้องสมุดและ คอลเลกชั่นที่คล้ายกัน ประกอบไปด้วยผลงานอันเกิดจากความพยายามในเชิงสติปัญญาและศิลปะ ทรัพยากรทางบรรณานุกรมในแบบจำลอง FRBR คือ เอนทิตีในกลุ่มที่ 1 ได้แก่ งาน รูปแบบการนำเสนอ รูปแบบการเผยแพร่ และหน่วยรายการ</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Nguồn thư mục</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một thực thể trong lĩnh vực thư viện và những bộ sưu tập tương tự bao gồm các sản phẩm trí tuệ hay sáng tạo nghệ thuật. Nguồn thư mục theo mô hình FRBR bao gồm những thực thể nhóm 1 như: tác phẩm, biểu ngữ, cách biểu thị và ấn phẩm.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Bibliographic universe  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicUniverse" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4685"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bibliographic universe</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The realm related to the collections of libraries, archives, museums, and other information communities.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Univers bibliografik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Fushë që përfshin koleksionet e bibliotekave, arkivave, muzeve dhe të bashkësive të tjera të informacionit.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">العالم الببليوغرافي</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هو العالم المتعلق بمجموعات المكتبات، الأرشيفات، المتاحف وجمعيات المعلومات الأخرى.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Библиографски универсум</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Сфера, която обхваща колекциите на библиотеки, архиви, музеи и други информационни общности.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Univers bibliogràfic</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Àmbit relatiu a les col•leccions de biblioteques, d’arxius, de museus, i d’altres comunitats de l’entorn de la informació.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">书目世界</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">与图书馆、档案馆、博物馆以及其它信息机构的收藏相关的领域。 </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Bibliografski univerzum</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Područje koje se odnosi na zbirke knjižnica, arhiva, muzeja i drugih informacijskih zajednica.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Bibliografické univerzum</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Sféra vztahující se ke sbírkám knihoven, archivů, muzeí a dalších informačních komunit.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Bibliografinen universumi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Kirjastojen, arkistojen, museoiden ja muiden informaatioyhteisöjen kokoelmiin liittyvät kohteet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Univers bibliographique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Domaine relatif aux collections de bibliothèques, archives, musées et autres communautés du monde de l’information.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bibliografisches Universum</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der Bereich, der sich auf die Bestände von Bibliotheken, Archiven, Museen und anderen Informationscommunitys bezieht.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Universo bibliografico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Il regno relativo alle raccolte delle biblioteche, degli archivi, dei musei e delle altre comunità dell’informazione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">書誌的宇宙</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">図書館、文書館、博物館・美術館およびその他の情報コミュニティのコレクションに関連する領域。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">서지 세계</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">도서관, 박물관, 기타 정보 커뮤니티의 집서와 관련된 세계</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfiskais visums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Joma, kas attiecas uz bibliotēku, arhīvu, muzeju un citu informācijas kopienu krājumiem.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Bibliografinis universumas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Sritis, jungianti bibliotekų, archyvų, muziejų ir kitų informacinių bendruomenių rinkinius.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Przestrzeń bibliograficzna</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Sfera związana ze zbiorami bibliotek, archiwów, muzeów i innych społeczności o charakterze informacyjnym.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Universo bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Domínio das coleções de bibliotecas, arquivos, museus e outras comunidades de informação.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Библиографический универсум </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Сфера,  объединяющая коллекции библиотек, архивов, музеев и других          информационных сообществ.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Bibliografski univerzum</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Oblast koja se odnosi na bibliotečke kolekcije, arhivske imuzejske zbirke i druge informacione zajednice.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Bibliografické univerzum</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Sféra vzťahujúca sa ku zbierkam knižníc, archívov, múzeí a ďalších informačných komunít.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bibliografski okvir</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Področje, ki obsega zbirke knjižnic, arhivov, muzejev in drugih informacijskih skupnosti.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Universo bibliográfico</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">El ámbito relacionado con las colecciones de las bibliotecas, archivos, museos y otras comunidades de información.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bibliografisk värld</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">De företeelser som är kopplade till samlingar på bibliotek, arkiv, museer och andra informationsverksamheter.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">โลกบรรณานุกรม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ขอบเขตที่เกี่ยวข้องกับคอลเลกชั่นของห้องสมุด หอจดหมายเหต พิพิธภัณฑ์และชุมชนสารสนเทศอื่น ๆ</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Tổ hợp thư mục</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Lĩnh vực liên quan đến những bộ sưu tập của thư viện, trung tâm lưu trữ, bảo tàng và cộng đồng thông tin khác.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Bibliographically significant  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicallySignificant" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4686"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Bibliographically significant</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A quality of an entity or attribute or relationship that has special meaning or value in the context of bibliographic resources.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Bibliografikisht i rëndësishëm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Cilësi e një entiteti, atributi ose lidhjeje që ka kuptim ose vlerë të veçantë në kontekstin e burimeve bibliografike.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الأهمية الببليوغرافية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هي ميزة لكيان أو حقل أو علاقة تحمل معنى خاص أو قيمة في سياق المصادر الببليوغرافية.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Библиографски значим(а)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Свойство на обект, атрибут или връзка, което има особено значение или стойност в контекста на библиографските ресурси.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Significatiu bibliogràficament</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Qualitat d’una entitat, un atribut o una relació que té un significat o un valor especial en el context dels recursos bibliogràfics.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">具有目录学意义的</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">实体、属性或关系的一种性质，在书目资源的环境中具有特别含义或赋值。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Bibliografski značajan</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Svojstvo entiteta ili atributa ili odnosa koje ima posebno značenje ili vrijednost u kontekstu bibliografske jedinice.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Bibliograficky významný</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Kvalita entity či atributu nebo vztahu, která má speciální význam či hodnotu v kontextu bibliografického zdroje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Bibliografisesti merkittävä</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Entiteetin tai attribuutin tai suhteen ominaisuus, jolla on erityinen merkitys tai arvo bibliografisten resurssien yhteydessä.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Significatif du point de vue bibliographique</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Qualité d’une entité, d’un attribut ou d’une relation qui a un sens ou un intérêt particulier dans le contexte des ressources bibliographiques.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bibliografisch relevant</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Qualität einer Entität oder ein Merkmal oder eine Beziehung, die im Kontext bibliografischer Ressourcen eine bestimmte Bedeutung oder einen bestimmten Wert hat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Bibliograficamente significativo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Qualità di un’entità o attributo o relazione che assume un senso o valore speciale nel contesto delle risorse bibliografiche.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">書誌的有意性</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">書誌的資源において、特別の意味もしくは価値を有する実体または属性または関連の質。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">서지적으로 중요한</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지자원의 맥락에서 특별한 의미나 가치를 갖는 개체나 속성, 관계의 질</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Bibliogrāfiski nozīmīgs</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Entītijas, atribūta vai attiecības īpašība, kurai ir īpaša nozīme vai vērtība bibliogrāfisko resursu kontekstā.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Bibliografiškai svarbus</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Entiteto arba atributo, arba santykio rūšis, kuri turi ypatingą reikšmę ar svarbą bibliografinių išteklių kontekste.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Elementy bibliograficznie znaczące</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Cecha jednostki, atrybut lub relacja, która ma szczególne znaczenie lub wartość w kontekście zasobów
bibliograficznych.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Bibliograficamente significativo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Qualidade de uma entidade, atributo ou relação que possui  significado ou valor especial no contexto de recursos bibliográficos.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Библиографически значимый </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Свойство объекта, или атрибута, или связи, которое имеет особое значение или ценность в контексте библиографических ресурсов. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Bibliografski značaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Osobina entiteta ili atributa, ili odnosa, koja ima posebno značenje ili vrednost u kontekstu bibliografskog izvora.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Bibliograficky významný</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Kvalita entity alebo atribútu alebo vzťahu, ktorá má špeciálny význam alebo hodnotu v kontexte bibliografického zdroja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bibliografsko pomemben</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Lastnost entitete, atributa ali odnosa, ki ima v kontekstu bibliografskih virov poseben pomen ali vrednost.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Bibliograficamente significativo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una cualidad de una entidad, atributo o relación que tiene un significado especial o alto valor en el contexto de los recursos bibliográficos.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bibliografiskt signifikant</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En egenskap hos en entitet, attribut eller relation som har en särskild mening eller är särskilt värdefull då det rör sig om bibliografiska resurser.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ตำแหน่งที่ตั้ง</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">คุณภาพของเอนทิตีหรือแอททริบิวท์ หรือความสัมพันธ์ที่มีความหมายหรือคุณค่าพิเศษในบริบทของทรัพยากรทางบรรณานุกรม</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Giá trị thư mục</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Đặc tính của thực thể, một vật hay mối quan hệ có ý nghĩa hay giá trị đặng biệt trong ngữ cảnh của nguồn thư mục.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Carrier type  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#CarrierType" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4687"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Carrier type</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A designation that reflects the format of the storage medium and housing of a carrier in combination with the type of intermediation device required to view, play, run, etc., the content of a resource. Carrier type reflects attributes of a manifestation.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Tipi i bartësit</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Përcaktim që pasqyron formatin e mjedisit depozitues dhe ruajtës të një bartësi, të kombinuar me tipin e pajisjes ndërmjetëse që duhet për ta parë, interpretuar, dëgjuar etj., përmbajtjen e burimit. Tipi i bartësit pasqyron atributet e një manifestimi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نوع الناقل</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هو تحديد يعكس شكل وسيط التخزين واستضافة ناقل بالإضافة إلى شكل الجهاز الوسيط الذي يستخدم لرؤية، عرض، تشغيل، الخ محتوى المصدر. نوع الناقل يعكس خصائص الإظهار.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Вид на носителя</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Означение за формáта на средството за съхраняване на информация и обвивката на носителя в съчетание с вида на възпроизвеждащото устройство, необходимо за да се прегледа, просвири, пусне в действие и т.н. съдържанието на ресурса. Видът на носителя отразява атрибутите на определена форма на физическо представяне.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Tipus de suport</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Designació que reflecteix el format del mitjà d’emmagatzematge i d’allotjament d’un suport en combinació amb el tipus de dispositiu intermediari requerit per visualitzar, posar en marxa, fer funcionar, etc., el contingut d’un recurs. El tipus de suport reflecteix atributs d’una manifestació.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">载体类型</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">反映载体的存储介质与安置的格式，并与对资源内容进行观看、放送、运行等所需的中介设备类型相结合的一种标识。载体类型反映载体表现的属性。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Vrsta nositelja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Oznaka formata medija za pohranu i spremnicu nositelja u kombinaciji s vrstom posrednog pomagala neophodnog za pregledavanje, prikazivanje, izvođenje itd. sadržaja jedinica. Vrsta nositelja odražava atribute pojavnog oblika.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Typ nosiče</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Označení vystihující formát paměťového média a jeho nosiče v kombinaci s typem zařízení, které je potřebné pro zprostředkování (zobrazení, přehrání, spuštění atd.) obsahu zdroje. Typ nosiče reflektuje atributy provedení.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Tallennetyyppi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Nimitys, joka kuvaa tietovälineen ulkomuotoa ja asua sekä laitetta, joka mahdollisesti tarvitaan resurssin sisällön tarkastelemiseksi, esittämiseksi, käynnistämiseksi jne. Tallennetyyppi heijastaa manifestaation attribuutteja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Support (Type de)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Appellation rendant compte de la présentation matérielle du support de stockage et de son conteneur, en combinaison avec le type de dispositif de médiation nécessaire pour visionner, activer, faire fonctionner, etc., le contenu d’une ressource. Le type de support rend compte des attributs d’une manifestation.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Art des Trägers</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Bezeichnung, welche das Format des Speichermediums und des Behältnisses eines Trägers [housing of a carrier] widerspiegelt, in Verbindung mit der Angabe, welches Wiedergabegerät benötigt wird, um den Inhalt der Ressource betrachten, abspielen, ausführen etc. zu können. Die Art des Trägers spiegelt die Merkmale einer Manifestation wider.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Tipo di supporto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Designazione che rispecchia il formato del mezzo di archiviazione e la custodia del supporto insieme con il tipo di apparecchiatura richiesta per vedere, ascoltare, scorrere, ecc. il contenuto di una risorsa. Il tipo di supporto rispecchia gli attributi di una manifestazione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">キャリア種別</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">資料の内容を見る、再生する、作動させる等のために必要とする媒介装置の種別と組み合わせて、格納する媒体の形式およびキャリアの収納方法を示す表示。キャリア種別は体現形の属性を示す。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">수록매체 유형</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">자원의 내용을 보고, 재생하고, 작동하는 데 필요한 중개 장치의 종류와 결합하여 저장매체와 매체가 수록된 외장 형식을 나타내는 명칭. 수록매체의 유형은 구현형의 속성을 반영한다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Datu nesēja veids</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Apzīmējums, kas atspoguļo glabāšanas datneša/medija un tā ietvara/apvalka formātu Apvienojumā ar resursa satura apskatīšanai, atskaņošanai, demonstrēšanai u.tml. nepieciešamo ierīci. Datu nesēja veids atspoguļo manifestācijas atribūtus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Laikmenos rūšis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Apibūdinimas, atspindintis informacijos laikymo formatą ir laikmenos fizinę formą, suderintą su tarpininkaujančio įtaiso, reikalingo ištekliaus turiniui peržiūrėti, atkurti, paleisti ir t. t., rūšimi. Laikmenos rūšis atspindi apraiškos atributus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Typ nośnika</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Oznaczenie, które odzwierciedla format nośnika danych i obudowę nośnika w połączeniu z typem urządzeń pośrednich koniecznych do obejrzenia, odtworzenia, uruchomienia itd. zawartości dokumentu. Typ nośnika
odzwierciedla atrybuty materializacji.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Tipo de suporte</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Designação que reflete o formato do meio de armazenamento e acondicionamento de um suporte em combinação com o tipo de mecanismo de intermediação necessário para visualizar, tocar, fazer funcionar, etc., o conteúdo de um recurso. O tipo de suporte reflete atributos de uma manifestação.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Тип носителя</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Обозначение, отражающее формат хранения средства и размещения носителя в сочетании с  типом воспроизводящего устройства, необходимого, чтобы просмотреть, проиграть, запустить, и т.п. содержание ресурса. Тип носителя отражает атрибуты воплощения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Fizički format</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Oznaka koja se odnosi na oblik medijuma za pohranjivanje i čuvanje nosioca informacije u kombinaciji sa oblikom prenosnog uređaja potrebnog za pregledanje, prikazivanje, pokretanje i slično sadržaja izvora.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Typ nosiča</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Označenie vystihujúce formát pamäťového média a jeho nosiča v kombinácii s typom zariadenia, ktoré je potrebné na sprostredkovanie (zobrazenie, prehranie, spustenie atď.) obsahu zdroja. Typ nosiča reflektuje atribúty prezentácie.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Vrsta nosilca</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oznaka formata medija in fizične oblike nosilca za shranjevanje skupaj z vrsto posredne naprave, ki je potrebna za gledanje, predvajanje itn. vsebine vira. Vrsta nosilca je atribut pojavne oblike.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Tipo de soporte</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una designación que refleja el formato del medio de almacenamiento y albergue de un soporte en combinación con el tipo de mecanismo intermediario que se requiere para la visualización, funcionamiento, movimiento, etc. del contenido de un recurso. El tipo de soporte refleja los atributos de una manifestación.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Bärartyp</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En beteckning som anger lagringsmediets format och bärarens placering tillsammans med den typ av spelare som behövs för att se, spela, köra etc. resursens innehåll. Manifestationens attribut återspeglas i bärartypen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ประเภทสื่อบรรจุ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อที่ใช้เรียกรูปแบบของสื่อบันทึก และเป็นที่อยู่ของสื่อบรรจุรวมกับประเภท ของเครื่องมือตัวกลางที่ใช้ในการชม เล่น ทำงาน เป็นต้น เนื้อหาทรัพยากร ประเภทของสื่อบรรจุเป็นแอททริบิวท์ของรูปแบบการเผยแพร่</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Dạng vật mang</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là tên phản ánh dạng thức của kho tàng và nhà cửa trong sự kết hợp với loại hình phương tiện yêu cầu để xem, để trình chiếu nội dung của nguồn lực. Dạng vật mang phản ánh thuộc tính của.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Type of carrier</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="vi">Hình thức tài liệu</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fi">Tietovälineen tyyppi</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ca">Suport, Tipus de</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fr">Type de support</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="it">Supporto, tipo di</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ko">수록매체의 유형</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="zh">载体的类型</skos:altLabel>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Collection  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Collection" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4688"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Collection</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">1. A real or virtual set of two or more works or parts of works combined or issued together.  
2. A real or virtual set of bibliographic resources held or created by a given institution.  </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Koleksion</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">1. Grup real ose virtual prej dy ose më shumë veprash ose pjesë të veprave të bashkuara ose të botuara së bashku. 
2. Grup real ose virtual burimesh bibliografike që mbahen ose janë krijuar nga një institucion i caktuar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">مجموعة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">1. مجموعة حقيقية أو افتراضية لعملين أو أكثر تم ضمهم أو إصدارهم معا.
2. مجموعة حقيقية أو افتراضية لمصادر ببليوغرافية مقتناه أو منشأة من قبل هيئة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Сборник</skos:prefLabel>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Concept  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Concept" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4692"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Concept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Koncept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">مفهوم</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Понятие</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Concepte</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An abstract notion or idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Nocion ose ide abstrakte.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">فكرة أو ملاحظة مجردة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Понятие	Абстрактна представа или идея.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Noció o idea abstracta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">概念</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一个抽象的观念或思想。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Pojam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Apstraktna zamisao ili ideja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Koncept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Abstraktní pojem či idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Käsite</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Abstrakti käsite tai idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Concept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Notion abstraite ou idée.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Begriff</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein abstrakter Gedanke oder eine Idee.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Concetto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Nozione astratta o idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">概念</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">抽象的観念や思想。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">개념</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">추상적 관념이나 사상</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Jēdziens</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Abstrakts priekšstats vai ideja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Sąvoka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Abstrakti sąvoka arba idėja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Pojęcie</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Abstrakcyjne wyobrażenie lub idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Conceito</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Noção ou ideia abstracta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Концепция</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Абстрактное понятие или идея.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Pojam</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Apstraktna zamisao ili ideja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Koncept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Abstraktný pojem alebo idea.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Pojem</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Abstrakcija ali ideja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Concepto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una idea o noción abstracta</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Koncept</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En abstrakt föreställning eller idé.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">แนวคิด</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ความคิดหรือความเข้าใจทางนามธรรม</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Khái niệm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một ý niêm hay ý nghĩa trừu tương.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Content type  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ContentType" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4693"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Content type</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A designation that reflects the fundamental form of communication in which the content is expressed and the human sense through which it is intended to be perceived. Content type reflects attributes of both work and expression.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Type of content</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="vi">Thể loại tài liệu</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Tipi i përmbajtjes</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نوع المحتوى</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Вид на съдържанието</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Tipus de contingut</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">内容类型</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">反映用以表达内容的基本交流形式以及用以感知内容的人类感官的一种标识。内容类型反映作品和内容表达两者的属性。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Vrsta sadržaja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Oznaka temeljnog oblika komunikacije u kojem je izražen sadržaj i ljudskog osjetila za koje je namijenjen doživljaj sadržaja. Vrsta sadržaja odražava atribute djela i izraza.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Typ obsahu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Sisältötyyppi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Art des Inhalts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">内容種別</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">내용 유형</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Satura veids</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Turinio rūšis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Typ zawartości</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Loại khái niệm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một tên gọi phản ánh hình thức cơ bản của sự giao tiếp khi nội dung được diễn đạt, khi sự hiểu biết của con người đạt được. Loại khái niệm phản ánh thuộc tính của cả tác phẩm và biểu ngữ.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ประเภทเนื้อหา</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Innehållstyp</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Tipo de contenido</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Përcaktim që pasqyron formën themelore të komunikimit me të cilën shprehet përmbajtja dhe sensin human të të kuptohet. Tipi i përmbajtjes pasqyron atributet si të veprës ashtu dhe të shprehjes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">هو تحديد يعكس شكل الاتصال الأساسي الذي يتم من خلاله التعبير عن المحتوى وإدراك الإنسان له. نوع المحتوى يعكس حقول العمل والتعبير.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Означение за основната форма на комуникация, в която е изразено и сетивото, с което е замислено да се възприема съдържанието. Видът на съдържанието отговаря на атрибутите на произведението и на формата на проявление.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Designació que reflecteix la forma fonamental de comunicació en la qual s’expressa el contingut i el sentit humà per mitjà del qual pretén ser percebut. El tipus de contingut reflecteix atributs de l’obra i de l’expressió.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Merkintö, joka kuvastaa sitä kommunikaation perusmuotoa, jolla teoksen sisältö on esitetty ja aistia, jonka kautta se on tarkoitettu havaittavaksi. Sisältötyyppi heijastaa sekä teoksen että ekspression attribuutteja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">内容が表現され、またそれを通じて人の感性が知覚することが意図されている伝達手段の基本的な形式を示す表示。内容種別は、著作および表現形の両者の属性を示す</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">내용을 표현하고 이를 통하여 인간의 감각이 이를 지각할 수 있는 기본적인 커뮤니케이션 형식을 반영한 명칭. 내용 유형은 저작과 표현형 모두의 속성을 반영한 것이다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En beteckning som anger den grundläggande kommunikationsform innehållet är uttryckt i och det mänskliga sinne genom vilket det är avsett att uppfattas. Både verket och uttryckets attribut återspeglas i innehållstypen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Označení vystihující základní formu komunikace, v níž je obsah vyjádřen, a lidský smysl, jehož prostřednictvím má být vnímán. Typ obsahu reflektuje atributy díla a vyjádření.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Bezeichnung, die die grundlegende Kommunikationsform, in der der Inhalt zum Ausdruck gebracht ist, und das menschliche Sinnesorgan, durch das der Inhalt erfasst werden soll, widerspiegelt. Die Art des Inhalts spiegelt sowohl Eigenschaften von Werken als auch von Expressionen wider.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Apzīmējums, kas atspoguļo komunikācijas pamatformu, kādā izteikts noteiktais saturs un cilvēka maņu orgānus, ar kādiem šo saturu paredzēts uztvert. Satura veids atspoguļo gan darba, gan izteiksmes atribūtus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Apibūdinimas, atspindintis pagrindinę pranešimo formą, kuria išreiškiamas turinys, ir tą žmogaus pojūtį, kuriuo jis suvokiamas. Turinio rūšis atspindi ir kūrinio, ir išraiškos atributus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Oznaczenie, które odzwierciedla podstawową formę przekazu, w której wyrażona jest treść, i ludzki zmysł, za pomocą którego będzie
ona odbierana. Typ zawartości odzwierciedla atrybuty zarówno dzieła, jak i realizacji.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una designación que refleja la forma fundamental de comunicación en la que se expresa el contenido y el sentido humano por el que se pretende que sea percibido. El tipo de contenido refleja atributos de obra y expresión.              </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อที่ใช้เรียกรูปแบบพื้นฐานของการสื่อสารที่แสดงเนื้อหา ผ่านการรับรู้ของ 	มนุษย์ที่ต้องการ ประเภทเนื้อหาเป็นแอททริบิวท์ของงานและรูปแบบการนำเสนอ</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Contenu (Type de)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Appellation rendant compte de la forme de communication selon laquelle un contenu est exprimé et de l’approche sensorielle qui lui est associée. Le type de contenu rend compte des attributs de l’œuvre et de l’expression.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Tipo di contenuto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Designazione che rispecchia la forma principale di comunicazione per mezzo della quale il contenuto è espresso e la facoltà sensoriale mediante la quale si vuole che sia compresa. Il tipo di contenuto rispecchia gli attributi sia dell’opera sia dell’espressione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Tipo de conteúdo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Designação que reflete a forma principal de comunicação na qual o conteúdo é expresso e o sentido humano através do qual se destina a ser percebido. O tipo de conteúdo reflete atributos tanto da obra como da expressão.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Тип содержания  </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Обозначение, отражающее основополагающую форму сообщения, в которой выражается содержание, и то человеческое чувство, с помощью которого оно должно быть воспринято. Тип содержания отражает атрибуты произведения и выражения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Vrsta sadržaja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Oznaka koja se odnosi na osnovni komunikacioni oblik u kome je izražen sadržaj i čulo kojim on treba da se spozna. Vrsta sadržaja odražava i atribute dela i atribute izraza.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Typ obsahu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Označenie vystihujúce základnú formu komunikácie, v ktorej je obsah vyjadrený, a ľudský zmysel, prostredníctvom ktorého má byť vnímaný. Typ obsahu reflektuje atribúty diela a vyjadrenia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Vrsta vsebine</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oznaka, ki pojasnjuje osnovno komunikacijsko obliko, prek katere je izražena vsebina, in opredeljuje človeški čut, s katerim jo je mogoče dojemati. Vrsta vsebine je atribut dela in izrazne oblike.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ca">Contingut, Tipus de</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="zh">内容的类型</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fi">Sisällön tyyppi</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="fr">Type de contenu</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="it">Contenuto, tipo di</skos:altLabel>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="ko">내용의 유형</skos:altLabel>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Controlled access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4694"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Controlled access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An access point recorded in an authority record. Controlled access points include authorized forms of names as well as those designated as variant forms.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#UncontrolledAccessPoint"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse e kontrolluar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول المضبوطة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Контролирана точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés controlat</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">受控检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Nadzirana pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Řízený selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Kontrolloitu hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès contrôlé</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Normierter Sucheinstieg</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso controllato</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">統制形アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">제어형 접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Kontrolētais piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Kontroliuojamas kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Kontrolowany punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso controlado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Контролируемая точка доступа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Kontrolisana pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Riadený selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Kontrolirana vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso controlado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Kontrollerad sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงควบคุม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập kiểm soát</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một điểm truy cập kiểm soát ghi lại hồ sơ tiêu để chuẩn. Điểm truy cập kiểm soát bao gồm các hình thức được phép của tên cũng như những tên được dùng như dạng thức biến thể.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse e regjistruar në një regjistrim termi të njësuar. Pikat hyrëse të kontrolluara përfshijnë format e autorizuara të emrave si dhe ato të përcaktuara si variante të formave të emrave.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Точка за достъп, записана в контролен запис. Контролираните точки за достъп включват както установените форми на имената (наименованията), така и определените за вариантни форми.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés inscrit en un registre d’autoritat.  Els punts d’accés controlats inclouen les formes autoritzades dels noms, així com les designades com a formes variants.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">被记录在规范记录中的一个检索点。
受控检索点包括名称的规范形式，以及确定为变异形式的那些检索点。它们可以：
　　-  以个人、家族和团体名称为基础，
    -  以作品、内容表达、载体表现和单件的名称（即题名）为基础，
　　-  是两个名称的组合形式，比如表示某一作品的名称/题名检索点，它将创作者名称与作品的题名组合在一起， 
　　-  以表达事件、实物,概念与地点的术语为基础，
　　-  以标准号码、分类记号之类的识别符为基础。
　　为了区分具有相同或相似名称的实体，可以对名称本身附加其它单元（比如日期）。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pristupnica zabilježena u preglednom zapisu.  Nadzirane pristupnice obuhvaćaju usvojene oblike imena kao i one oblike koji se smatraju neusvojenima.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Auktoriteettitietueen hakutieto.  Kontrolloituja hakutietoja ovat sekä nimien auktorisoidut muodot että nimen varianttimuodot.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès recensé dans une notice d’autorité.  Les points d’accès contrôlés comprennent les formes autorisées des noms aussi bien que celles désignées comme variantes de formes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Point d’accès recensé dans une notice d’autorité.  Les points d’accès contrôlés comprennent les formes autorisées des noms aussi bien que celles désignées comme variantes de formes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso registrato in una registrazione di autorità. Punti di accesso controllati includono forme autorizzate dei nomi come pure quelle designate come forme varianti.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">典拠レコードに記録されたアクセスポイント。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso incluído num registo de autoridade. Os pontos de acesso controlados incluem as formas autorizadas, assim como as chamadas formas variantes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Точка доступа, занесенная в авторитетную запись.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pristupna tačka zabeležena u normativnom zapisu.  Kontrolisane pristupne tačke podrazumevaju normirane oblike imena kao i one koji su označeni kao varijantni oblici.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un punto de acceso recogido en un registro de autoridad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En sökingång som registrerats i en auktoritetspost. Kontrollerade sökingångar innefattar både auktoriserade namnformer och de som betecknats som variantformer.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่บันทึกในรายการควบคุม</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقاط الوصول المضبوطة تشمل الأشكال المقننة بالإضافة إلى الأشكال التي تم اعتبارها أشكال مختلفة. ويمكن أن تكون:
–	مبنية على أسماء أشخاص، عائلات وهيئات،
–	مبنية على أسماء (أي، عناوين) أعمال، تعبيرات، مظاهر، وأوعية،
–	مكونة من اسمين، كما في حالة نقطة الوصول الاسم/العنوان والتي تمثل العمل الذي يضم اسم الصانع مع عنوان العمل،
–	مبنية على مصطلحات للأحداث، الأشياء، المفاهيم، والأماكن،
–	مبنية على محددات مثل الأرقام المعيارية، رموز التصنيف، الخ.
يمكن إضافة عناصر أخرى للاسم في حد ذاته (مثل التواريخ) لغرض التمييز بين كيانات لها نقس الاسم أو أسماء متشابهة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Selekční údaj zaznamenaný v autoritním záznamu. Řízené selekční údaje zahrnují jak autorizované formy jmen tak i variantní formy jmen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Autoritatīvajā ierakstā fiksētais piekļuves punkts. Kontrolētie piekļuves punkti ietver personvārdu/nosaukumu un to atšķirīgo variantu autorizētās formas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Kreipties elementas, įrašytas į autoritetinį įrašą.  Kontroliuojami kreipties elementai apima ir aprobuotas vardų formas, ir tas formas, kurios laikomos formų variantais.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Punkt dostępu zapisany w rekordzie wzorcowym.  Kontrolowane punkty dostępu obejmują ujednolicone formy nazw oraz formy uznane za warianty.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Selekčný údaj zaznamenaný v autoritatívnom zázname. </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Vstopna točka, zabeležena v normativnem zapisu. Kontrolirane vstopne točke vključujejo normativne oblike imen ter tiste, ki so določene kot variantne.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Conventional name  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ConventionalName" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4695"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Conventional name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A name, other than the official name, by which a corporate body, place, or thing has come to be known.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Emër konvencional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الاسم الشائع أو الاصطلاحي</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Nom convencional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">اسم غير الاسم الرسمي، والذي تعرف به هيئة، مكان، أو شيء.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Emër, i ndryshëm nga emri zyrtar, me anë të të cilit një organizëm, vend ose objekt është bërë i njohur.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Nom, diferent de l’oficial, pel qual una entitat corporativa, un lloc o una cosa ha esdevingut conegut.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">惯用名称</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一个团体、地点或事物的广为人知的名称，但不包括正式名称。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Uobičajeno ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Ime po kojem je poznato neko korporativno tijelo, mjesto ili stvar, a nije njihovo službeno ime.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Konvenční jméno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Vakiintunut nimi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Nom conventionnel</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Gebräuchlicher Name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Nome convenzionale</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">慣用名</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">관용명</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Vispārpieņemtais nosaukums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Sutartinis vardas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Nazwa zwyczajowa</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Nome convencional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Uobičajeno ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Konvenčné meno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Konvencionalno ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Nombre convencional</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Konventionellt namn</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ชื่อที่เป็นที่นิยม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Tên thông dụng</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tên, hay nói cách khác là tên chính thức, mà qua đó đoàn thể, địa danh hay sự vật được biết đến.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Ett namn som inte är det officiella, men under vilket en institution, plats eller föremål kommit att bli känt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Nimi, jolla yhteisö, paikka tai asia tunnetaan, joka kuitenkaan ei aina ole virallinen nimi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Nom, autre que le nom officiel, sous lequel on connaît une collectivité, un lieu, ou une chose.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein vom offiziellen Namen abweichender Name, unter dem eine Körperschaft, ein Ort oder eine Sache bekannt ist.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Nome, diverso dal nome ufficiale, per mezzo del quale un ente, luogo, oggetto è diventato conosciuto.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">公的な名称とは異なるが、それによって団体・場所・物事が知られてきた名称。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Nome, outro que não o oficial, pelo qual uma colectividade (entidade), lugar ou objeto se tornou conhecido.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Ime ili naziv koji se razlikuje od zvaničnog imena ili naziva, po kome je kolektivno telo, mesto ili stvar poznata.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un nombre, distinto del oficial, por el que una entidad corporativa, lugar o cosa ha llegado a ser más conocido.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อนิติบุคคล สถานที่ หรือสิ่งของที่เป็นที่รู้จักดี ที่นอกเหนือไปจากชื่อ ทางการ</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Jméno, jiné než oficiální, pod kterým je korporace, místo či věc známa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Nosaukums, kas nav oficiālais nosaukums, bet ar kuru institūcija, vieta vai priekšmets ir vispārpazīstams.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vardas, kuris skiriasi nuo oficialaus, pagal kurį žinomas
kolektyvas, vieta ar daiktas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Nazwa powszechnie przyjęta dla ciała zbiorowego, miejsca lub rzeczy.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Meno, iné než oficiálne, pod ktorým je korporácia, miesto alebo vec známa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Neuradno ime, po katerem je znana korporacija, kraj ali predmet.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#PreferredName"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Общоприето име (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Име (наименование), различно от официалното, под което са известни колективен орган, място или друг обект.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">단체나 장소, 사물의 공식명 이외에 널리 알려진 이름</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Общепринятое имя (наименование)  </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Имя  (наименование), отличное от официального, под которым известны организация,  место или вещь.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Corporate body  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#CorporateBody" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4696"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Corporate body</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An organisation or group of persons and/or organisations that is identified by a particular name and that acts, or may act, as a unit.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Organizëm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الهيئة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Колективен орган</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Entitat corporativa</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">团体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Korporativno tijelo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Korporace</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Yhteisö</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Organisaatio, joukko henkilöitä tai järjestöjä, jotka tunnetaan erityisellä nimellä ja jotka toimivat tai voivat toimia yhtenä kokonaisuutena.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Collectivité</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Körperschaft</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Ente</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">由特定名称识别，并作为一个单位进行活动或可能活动的一个组织或一群个人和/或组织。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">団体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">特定の名称によって識別され、かつ一体として活動するか、もしくは活動することのありうる組織、あるいは個人および／または組織の集合。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">단체</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">특정 명칭으로 식별되고 하나의 단위로 활동하거나 활동할 수 있는 개인의 조직이나 집단 및 기관</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Institūcija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Kolektyvas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Ciało zbiorowe</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Организация </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Организация или группа лиц и/или организаций, которые идентифицируются особым наименованием и которые действуют или могут действовать как единое целое.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Kolektivno telo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Ustanova ili grupa osoba i/ili ustanova koje se identifikuju prema određenom imenu i koje deluju ili mogu da deluju kao celina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Korporácia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Korporacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Entidad corporativa</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Institution</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">นิติบุคคล</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Đoàn thể</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một tổ chức, nhóm người hay nhiều tổ chức được xác định bởi một tên gọi riêng biệt và hoạt động hay có thể hoạt động như một đơn vị.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">หน่วยงานหนึ่งหรือกลุ่มบุคคลหนึ่งและ/หรือหน่วยงานต่าง ๆ ที่ถูกระบุด้วยชื่อ
เฉพาะและมี (หรืออาจมี) กิจกรรมเป็นหน่วยเดียวกัน</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Organizatë ose grup personash dhe/ose organizatash të identifikuar me një emër të veçantë dhe që vepron, ose mund të veprojë, si një njësi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">منظمة أو مجموعة من الأفراد/أو المنظمات المعروفة باسم معين والتي تعمل أو قد تعمل كوحدة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Организация или група от лица и/или организации, които се идентифицират с определено наименование и действат или биха могли да действат като едно цяло.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Organització o grup d’individus i/o d’organitzacions identificat per un nom concret i que actua, o pot actuar, com una unitat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Ustanova ili skupina osoba i/ili ustanova koje identificira određeno ime i koja djeluje ili može djelovati kao cjelina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Organisme, groupe de personnes ou d’organismes identifié par un nom particulier et qui agit, ou peut agir, comme un tout.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Organisation oder eine Gruppe von Personen und/oder Organisationen, die durch einen bestimmten Namen bezeichnet wird, und die als Einheit handelt bzw. handeln kann.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Organizzazione o gruppo di persone e/o di organizzazioni, identificato da un particolare nome e che agisce, o può agire, come un’unità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una organización o grupo de personas y/o de organizaciones que se identifica por un nombre específico y que actúa, o puede actuar, como una unidad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En organisation eller grupp av personer och/eller organisationer som identifieras med ett särskilt namn och som uppträder, eller kan uppträda, som en enhet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Organizace či skupina osob a/nebo organizací, která je identifikována určitým jménem a která jedná nebo může jednat jako celek.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Organizācija vai personu un/vai organizāciju grupa, kas identificējama pēc konkrēta nosaukuma un darbojas vai var darboties kā vienība.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Organizacija ar asmenų ir (arba) organizacijų grupė, kuri
identifikuojama pagal konkretų vardą ir kuri veikia arba gali veikti kaip visuma.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Organizacja lub grupa osób i/lub organizacji, która jest
rozpoznawana pod nazwą własną i, która działa lub może działać jako zespół.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Organizácia alebo skupina osôb a/alebo organizácií, ktorá je identifikovaná určitým menom, a ktorá koná alebo môže konať ako celok.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Organizacija ali skupina ljudi in/ali organizacij, ki jo identificira določeno ime in deluje oziroma more delovati kot enota.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Colectividade (entidade)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Organização ou grupo de pessoas e/ou organizações que se identifica por determinado nome e actua, ou pode actuar, como uma unidade.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Creator  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Creator" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4674"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Creator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">저작의 지적 또는 예술적 내용에 책임을 지닌 개인이나 가족, 단체</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Person, Familie oder Körperschaft, die für den intellektuellen oder künstlerischen Inhalt eines Werks verantwortlich ist.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">著作の知的・芸術的内容に責任をもつ個人、家族または団体。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Persona, dzimta vai institūcija, kas atbildīga par darba intelektuālo vai māksliniecisko saturu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A person, family, or corporate body responsible for the intellectual or artistic content
of a work.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oseba, rodbina ali korporacija, odgovorna za intelektualno ali umetniško vsebino dela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Personne, famille ou collectivité responsable du contenu intellectuel ou artistique d'une œuvre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Osoba, rodina či korporace odpovědná za intelektuální či umělecký obsah díla.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Pessoa, família ou colectividade (entidade) responsável pelo conteúdo intelectual ou artístico de uma obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Person, familje ose organizëm përgjegjës për përmbajtjen intelektuale ose artistike të një vepre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">หรือนิติบุคคลหนึ่งที่รับผิดชอบต่อเนื้อหาทางสติปัญญาและ
ศิลปะของงาน</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một người, gia đình hay đoàn thể chịu trách nhiệm về nội dụng nghệ thuật hay trí tuệ của một tác phẩm.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Osoba, obitelj ili korporativno tijelo odgovorno za intelektualni ili umjetnički sadržaj djela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Лицо, род, или организация, ответственные за интеллектуальное или художественное содержание произведения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">对一部作品的知识或艺术内容负有责任的个人、家族或团体。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">شخص، عائلة أو هيئة مسئولة عن المحتوى الفكري أو الفني للعمل.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una persona, familia o entidad corporativa responsable del contenido intelectual o artístico de una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Osoba, rodina alebo korporácia zodpovedná za intelektuálny alebo umelecký obsah diela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En person, familj eller institution som ansvarar för det intellektuella eller konstnärliga innehållet i ett verk.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Persona, famiglia o ente responsabile del contenuto intellettuale o artistico di un’opera.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Создатель</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Créateur</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ผู้สร้างสรรค์ผลงาน</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Radītājs</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">创作者</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Stvaratelj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Ustvarjalec</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الصانع</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Tvorca</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Creador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Creatore</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">저작자</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">作成者</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Criador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Tvůrce</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Upphovsman</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Geistiger Schöpfer</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Krijues</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Sáng tạo viên</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Създател</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Лице, фамилия или колективен орган, които носят отговорност за интелектуалното или художественото съдържание на произведение.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Creador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Persona, família o entitat corporativa responsable del contingut intel•lectual o artístic d’una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Tekijä</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Henkilö, perhe/suku tai yhteisö, joka on vastuussa teoksen tiedollisesta tai taiteellisesta sisällöstä.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Kūrėjas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Asmuo, giminė ar kolektyvas, atsakingi už intelektinį ar meninį kūrinio turinį.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Twórca</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Osoba, rodzina lub ciało zbiorowe odpowiedzialne za intelektualną lub artystyczną zawartość dzieła.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Stvaralac</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Osoba, porodica ili kolektivno telo odgovorno za intelektualni ili umetnički sadržaj dela.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Agent"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Descriptive cataloguing  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#DescriptiveCataloguing" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4697"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Descriptive cataloguing</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The part of cataloguing that provides both descriptive data and non-subject access points.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#SubjectCataloguing"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#BibliographicDescription"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Katalogim përshkrues</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الفهرسة الوصفية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Описателна каталогизация</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Catalogació descriptiva</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pjesa e katalogimit që jep të dhënat përshkruese dhe pikat hyrëse jo për subjekte.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">جزء الفهرسة الذي يوفر البيانات الوصفية ونقاط الوصول غير الموضوعية.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Частта от каталогизацията, осигуряваща описателни данни и точки за достъп, които не са свързани със съдържанието.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Part de la catalogació que proporciona dades descriptives i punts d’accés, exclosos els de matèries.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">描述性编目</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">编目工作的组成部分，提供描述性数据和非主题检索点。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Deskriptivna katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Dio katalogizacije koji osigurava opisne podatke i pristupnice koje nisu predmetnice.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Popisná katalogizace</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Kuvaileva luettelointi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Catalogage descriptif</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Formalerschließung</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der Teil der Erschließung, der sowohl beschreibende Daten als auch nicht auf den Inhalt bezogene Sucheinstiege erstellt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Partie du catalogage qui établit à la fois les données descriptives et les points d’accès autres que les accès matière.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Catalogazione descrittiva</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">記述目録作業</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">目録作業において、記述データおよび主題以外のアクセスポイントの両者を与える部分。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">기술목록법</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">기술 데이터와 비주제 접근점 모두를 제시하는 목록기법의 한 영역</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Aprakstošā kataloģizācija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Aprašomasis katalogavimas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Katalogowanie formalne</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Catalogação descritiva</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">A parte do processamento bibliográfico que fornece quer os dados descritivos quer os pontos de acesso que não são de assunto.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Описательная каталогизация </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Часть каталогизации, которая обеспечивает и описательные данные, и нетематические точки доступа.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Deskriptivna katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Popisná katalogizácia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Opisna katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Catalogación descriptiva</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Deskriptiv katalogisering</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">การลงรายการเชิงบรรยาย</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Mục lục mô tả</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là một phần của mục lục cung cấp dữ liệu mô tả và những điểm truy cập không theo chủ đề.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Se osa luettelointia, joka sisältää sekä kuvailutiedot että muut kuin sisältöä koskevat hakutiedot.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">La parte di catalogazione che fornisce sia dati descrittivi sia punti di accesso che non siano di soggetto.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Deo katalogizacije koji obezbeđuje i opisne podatke ipristupne tačke koje nisu predmetne odrednice.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La parte de la catalogación que proporciona información descriptiva y puntos de acceso, excluyendo los de materias.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Den del av katalogiseringen som redovisar beskrivande data och och sökingångar som inte har med ämnet att göra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Kataloģizācijas daļa, kas nodrošina gan aprakstošos datus, gan piekļuves punktus (izņemot priekšmetu).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Katalogavimo dalis, kuri pateikia ir aprašomuosius duomenis, ir kreipties elementus, išskyrus dalykinius terminus ir
klasifikacinius indeksus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Del katalogizacije, ki preskrbi tako opisne podatke kot tudi vstopne točke, ki niso povezane z vsebino.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ส่วนของการลงรายการที่ให้ข้อมูลเชิงบรรยายและ จุดเข้าถึงที่ไม่ใช่หัวเรื่อง

</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Část katalogizace, jejímž výsledkem jsou jak popisné, tak selekční údaje s výjimkou věcných.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Część katalogowania, która uwzględnia opis formalny bez rzeczowych punktów dostępu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Časť katalogizácie, ktorej výsledkom sú popisné a selekčné údaje s výnimkou vecných.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Entity  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Entity" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4698"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Entity</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Something that has a unitary and self-contained character; something that has independent or separate existence; an abstraction, ideal concept, object of thought, or transcendental object.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Entitet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الكيان</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Обект</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Entitat</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">实体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Entitet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Ono što je jedinstveno i potpuno; ono što postoji nezavisno ili zasebno; apstrakcija, idealan pojam, objekt mišljenja ili transcendentalan objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Entita</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Entiteetti</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Entité</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Entität</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Quelque chose ayant un caractère unitaire et autonome ; quelque chose qui existe d’une façon indépendante ou singulière ; abstraction, concept, objet de pensée, ou objet transcendantal.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Něco, co má unitární a samostatný charakter; co existuje nezávisle či samostatně; abstrakce, ideový koncept, objekt myšlení či transcendentální objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Etwas, das einen einheitlichen und in sich geschlossenen Charakter hat, etwas, das unabhängig ist oder gesondert existiert, eine Abstraktion, ein Begriff, ein Gedankengut oder ein metaphysisches Objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Entità</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Qualcosa che ha un carattere unitario e un contenuto in sé; qualcosa che ha un’esistenza indipendente o separata; un’astrazione, un concetto ideale, un oggetto di un pensiero o un oggetto trascendente.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">実体</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">一個の単位をもち自己完結する性格をもつもの；独自または個別の存在をもつもの；抽象概念、思想的概念、思考対象、観念的対象。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">개체</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">하나의 단위로 자기완결의 특성을 지닌 사물, 독립된 혹은 독자적으로 존재하는 사물, 추상적 개념, 이상적 개념, 사고의 대상, 선험적 대상</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Entītija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Entitetas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Jednostka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Entidade</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Объект</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Нечто, обладающее целостными и самостоятельными свойствами, нечто независимое и отдельно существующее; абстракция, идеальная концепция, предмет мысли или трансцендентальный предмет.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Algo que possui um carácter unitário e auto-contido; algo que tem existência independente ou separada; uma abstracção, conceito ideal, objeto de pensamento ou transcendental.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Entita</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Entiteta</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Entidad</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Algo que tiene carácter unitario y contenido en sí mismo; algo que tiene independencia o existencia individual; una abstracción, concepto ideal, objeto del pensamiento u objeto trascendental.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Entitet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">เอนทิตี</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Thực thể</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là vật thể có một đặc điểm đơn nhất và độc lập, là vật thể tồn tại độc lập hay riêng rẽ, là sự trừu tượng hóa, là khái niệm ý tưởng, là đối tượng tư duy, hay đối tượng mơ hồ.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Diçka që ka karakter unik dhe të pavarur, diçka që ka ekzistencë të pavarur ose të veçantë; abstraksion, koncept ideal, objekt i mendimit ose objekt idealist.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Нещо, което има цялостен и самостоятелен характер. Нещо, което съществува отделно и независимо. Абстракция, идеално понятие, предмет на мисълта или трансцедентен обект.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Quelcom que té un caràcter unitari i autònom; quelcom que té una existència independent o separada; abstracció, concepte ideal, objecte de pensament o objecte transcendental.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Niečo, čo má unitárny a samostatný charakter; čo existuje nezávisle alebo samostatne; abstrakcia, ideový koncept, objekt myslenia alebo transcendentálny objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">สิ่งใดสิ่งหนึ่งที่เป็นหน่วยเดียวและมีคุณลักษณะในตัวเอง สิ่งใดสิงหนึ่งที่มีการดำรงอยู่อย่าง เป็นอิสระหรือแยกออกมา นามธรรม ความคิดอุดมคติ วัตถุทางความคิดหรือวัตถุทางจิตวิญญาณ</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Kar ima edinstven in individualni značaj;  kar obstaja neodvisno in ločeno od drugega; abstrakcija, idejni koncept, miselni objekt, transcendentalni objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Kaut kas unitārs un patstāvīgs; kaut kas neatkarīgi un atsevišķi pastāvošs; abstrakcija, iedomāts jēdziens, domas objekts vai transcendentāls objekts.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Tai, kam būdingas vientisumas ir savarankiškumas; tai, kas nepriklausomai ar atskirai egzistuoja; abstrakcija, ideali koncepcija, minties objektas arba transcendentinis objektas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Coś, co ma jednostkowy i samodzielny charakter, coś co posiada niezależną i oddzielną egzystencję; abstrakcja, pojęcie, obiekt myśli lub obiekt transcendentny.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">On luonteeltaan yhtenäinen ja muista riippumaton olio. Se on olemassa itsenäisenä tai erillisenä; abstraktio, ihanne, ajattelun kohde tai transkendentaalinen kohde.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">شيء له خصائصه كوحدة مميزة ... شيء له وجود مستقل أو منفصل ... تجريد، مفهوم مثالي، شيء فكري، أو شيء جوهري.
أمثلة أنواع الكيانات في المتطلبات الوظيفية للتسجيلات الببليوغرافية FRBR)) والمتطلبات الوظيفية للبيانات الاستنادية FRAD)) تشمل الإنتاج الفكري والفني (العمل، التعبير، المظهر، والوعاء)؛ العاملون (شخص، عائلة، هيئة) المسئولون عن صنع هذا المحتوى الفكري أو الفني، إنتاج وبث المحتوى في شكل مادي، أو المسئول عن صيانة المنتج ؛ أو موضوع التعبير الفكري أو الفني (عمل، تعبير، مظهر، وعاء، شخص، عائلة، هيئة، مفهوم، شيء، حدث، مكان)</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">具有单一与自我独立特征的某些事物；独立或单独存在的某些事物；一种抽象的观念、思想的概念、思考的客体，或先验的对象。
FRBR和FRAD实体类型的实例包括，知识或艺术创作的产品（作品、内容表达、载体表现和单件）；对知识或艺术内容的创作、对物理形式之内容的制作和散发，或对产品保管的维持负有责任的代理（即个人、家族、团体）；或者一部作品的主题（作品、内容表达、载体表现、单件、个人、家族、团体、概念、实物、事件、地点）。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">(Viss) avgränsad och enhetlig företeelse av konkret el. abstrakt slag.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Essential access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#EssentialAccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4699"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Essential access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An access point based on a main attribute or relationship of an entity in a bibliographic or authority record that ensures retrieval and identification of that record.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AdditionalAccessPoint"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse kryesore</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول الأساسية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Основна точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés essencial</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">基本检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Neophodna pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Základní selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Ensisijainen hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès essentiel</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Notwendiger Sucheinstieg</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso indispensabile</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">中核的アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">필수 접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Svarīgākais piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Esminis kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Podstawowy punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso essencial</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Обязательная точка доступа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Glavna pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Základný selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Bistvena vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso esencial</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Grundläggande sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่จำเป็น</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập cần thiết</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một điểm truy cập dựa vào thuộc tính hay mối quan hệ chính yếu của một thực thể trong biểu ghi thư mục hay biểu ghi tiêu đề chuẩn nhằm đảm bảo cho sự truy cập và tính xác định của biểu ghi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Es un punto de acceso basado en un atributo principal  o relación de una entidad en un registro bibliográfico o de autoridad,  que asegura la recuperación e identificación de dicho registro.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En sökingång baserad på entitetens huvudattribut eller huvudrelation i en bibliografisk post eller en auktoritetspost, som garanterar att posten ifråga kan återfinnas och identifieras.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Точка доступа, основанная на главном атрибуте или связи  объекта в библиографической или авторитетной записи, которая обеспечивает поиск и идентификацию этой записи.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso baseado nos principais atributos e relações de cada entidade constante nos registos bibliográficos ou de autoridade, que assegura a identificação e recuperação desses registos.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pristupna tačka zasnovana na glavnom atributu ili odnosu entiteta u bibliografskom ili normativnom zapisu koja obezbeđuje pretraživanje i identifikaciju tog zapisa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">서지레코드나 전거레코드에서 각 개체의 주된 속성과 개체간의 관계에 기초한 접근점으로서, 해당 레코드를 검색하고 식별하기 위한 것이다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">書誌レコードまたは典拠レコードの中の、実体の主要な属性または関連に基づくアクセスポイントであり、そのレコードの検索および識別を確実にする</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso basato su un attributo o una relazione principali di un’entità in una registrazione bibliografica o di autorità, che assicura il recupero e l’identificazione di quella registrazione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Sucheinstieg, der auf den Hauptmerkmalen und -beziehungen jeder Entität in bibliografischen Datensätzen oder Normdatensätzen basiert und sicherstellt, dass solche Datensätze gefunden und identifiziert werden können.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès basé sur le principal attribut ou sur la principale relation d’une entité dans une notice bibliographique ou d’autorité, et qui permet à cette notice d’être recherchée et identifiée.  </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Bibliografisen tai auktoriteettitietueen hakutieto, jonka perustana on tietueen löytyvyyden ja identifioinnin kannalta tärkein attribuutti tai suhde.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pristupnica koja se temelji na glavnom atributu ili odnosu entiteta u bibliografskom ili preglednom zapisu, a osigurava pronalaženje i identifikaciju toga zapisa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">以书目记录或规范记录中某一实体的主要属性或关系为基础的检索点，以确保对那些记录的检索和识别。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés basat en un atribut o una relació principal d’una entitat en un registre bibliogràfic o d’autoritat que assegura la recuperació i identificació d’aquest registre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Точка за достъп, основана на първостепенни атрибут или връзка на обекта в библиографския или контролния запис, която осигурява откриването и идентифицирането на записа.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول المبنية على الحقول والعلاقات الأساسية لكل كيان في التسجيلات الببليوغرافية والاستنادية، والتي تضمن الاسترجاع والتعرف على هذه التسجيلات.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse bazuar në një atribut kryesor ose lidhje të një entiteti në një regjistrim bibliografik ose regjistrim termi të njësuar që siguron gjetjen dhe identifikimin e atij regjistrimi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Selekční údaj založený na hlavním atributu či vztahu entity v bibliografickém či autoritním záznamu, který zajišťuje vyhledání a identifikaci záznamu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Piekļuves punkts, kas pamatojas uz entītijas galveno atribūtu vai attiecību bibliogrāfiskajā vai autoritatīvajā ierakstā un kurš nodrošina šī ieraksta identifikāciju un izguvi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Kreipties elementas, pagrįstas pagrindiniu entiteto atributu ar santykiu bibliografiniame ar autoritetiniame įraše, palengvinantis šio įrašo paiešką ir identifikavimą.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Punkt dostępu, oparty na głównym
atrybucie lub relacji jednostki w rekordzie bibliograficznym lub wzorcowym, zapewniający wyszukiwanie i identyfikację tego rekordu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Selekčný údaj založený na hlavnom atribúte alebo vzťahu entity v bibliografickom alebo autoritatívnom zázname, ktorý zabezpečuje vyhľadanie a identifikáciu záznamu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Vstopna točka v bibliografskem ali normativnem zapisu, ki temelji na glavnem atributu ali odnosu, v katerem je entiteta, ter omogoča najdenje in identifikacijo tega zapisa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่มาจากแอททริบิวท์และความสัมพันธ์หลักของ เอนทิตีในรายการบรรณานุกรมและรายการควบคุม เพื่อการค้นคืนและระบุระเบียนเหล่านั้น
</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Event  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Event" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4700"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Event</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An action or occurrence.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Ngjarje</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Събитие</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الحدث</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">فعل أو حدوث</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Veprim ose ndodhi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Действие или явление.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Esdeveniment</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">事件</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一个行动或一件发生的事情。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Acció o fet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Događaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Událost</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Tapahtuma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Événement</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Ereignis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Evento</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">出来事</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">사건</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Notikums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Įvykis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Wydarzenie</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Evento</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Событие</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Događaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Dogodek</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Acontecimiento</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Händelse</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">เหตุการณ์</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Sự kiện</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một hành động hay sự việc diễn ra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">การกระทำหรือกิจกรรม</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En handling eller tilldragelse.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una acción o suceso.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Djelovanje ili pojava.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Dejanje ali dogajanje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Delovanje ili pojava.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Действие или явление.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ação ou ocorrência.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Działanie lub zdarzenie.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Veiksmas arba faktas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Darbība vai gadījums.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">행위나 일어난 일</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">行為や事件。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Azione o avvenimento.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine abgeschlossene Handlung oder eine Begebenheit.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Fait accompli ou survenu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Toiminta tai tilaisuus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Činnost nebo akce.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Udalosť</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Činnosť alebo akcia.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Expression  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Expression" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4701"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Expression</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The intellectual or artistic realisation of a work.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Shprehje</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">التعبير</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Форма на проявление</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Интелектуалното или художествено осъществяване на произведение.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Realizimi intelektual ose artistik i një vepre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Expressió</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">内容表达</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一部作品的知识或艺术的实现。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Realització intel•lectual o artística d’una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">الإدراك الفكري أو الفني للعمل</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Izraz</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Intelektualna ili umjetnička realizacija djela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Vyjádření</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Ekspressio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Expression</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Expression</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Espressione</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">表現形</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">표현형</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Izteiksme</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Išraiška</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Realizacja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Expressão</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Выражение</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Izraz</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Vyjadrenie</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Izrazna oblika</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Expresión</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Uttryck</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รูปแบบการนำเสนอ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Biểu ngữ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Teoksen tiedollinen tai taiteellinen toteutus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Réalisation intellectuelle ou artistique d’une œuvre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Die intellektuelle oder künstlerische Umsetzung eines Werks.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Realizzazione intellettuale o artistica di un’opera.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">著作の知的・芸術的実現</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">저작의 지적 또는 예술적 실현물</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Realização intelectual ou artística de uma obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Интеллектуальная или художественная форма реализации произведения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Intelektualna ili umetnička realizacija dela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La realización intelectual o artística de una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Det intellektuella eller konstnärliga förverkligandet av ett verk.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">การแสดงออกทางสติปัญญาหรือศิลปะของงาน</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Sự hiện thực hóa mang tính trí tuệ và nghệ thuật của tác phẩm.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Intelektuální či umělecká realizace díla.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Darba īstenošanas intelektuālā vai mākslinieciskā forma.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Intelektinis ar meninis kūrinio realizavimas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Intelektualna lub artystyczna reprezentacja dzieła.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Intelektuálna alebo umelecká realizácia diela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Intelektualna ali umetniška izvedba dela.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Family  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Family" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4702"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Family</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Two or more persons related by birth, marriage, adoption, or similar legal status, or otherwise presenting themselves as a family.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Familje</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">العائلة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Фамилия</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Família</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">家族</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Obitelj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Rodina</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Famille</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Família</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Род</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Porodica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Rodina</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Rodbina</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Familia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Familj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ครอบครัว</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Gia đình</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Familie</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Famiglia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">家族</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">가족</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Dzimta</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Giminė</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Rodzina</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Duas ou mais pessoas relacionadas pelo nascimento, casamento, adoção ou outro estado legal semelhante, ou que de outro modo se apresentam como uma família.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Два лица или более, связанных рождением, браком, усыновлением или аналогичным правовым статусом, либо любым другим способом, представляющие собой одну семью.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Dy ose më shumë persona të afërm nga lindja, martesa, birësimi ose status tjetër ligjor, ose që e paraqesin veten si familje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">شخصين أو أكثر مرتبطين بعلاقة الرحم، الزواج، التبني، أو وضع قانوني مشابه، أو يقدموا أنفسهم كعائلة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Две или повече лица, свързани по рождение, чрез брак, осиновяване или друг подобен правен статус или представящи се по друг начин за семейство.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Dues o més persones relacionades per naixement, matrimoni, adopció o per un estatus legal similar o que, si més no, es presenten a elles mateixes com a família.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">在出生、婚姻、抚养或类似的法律身份方面存在关系的两个或多个个人，或以其它方式将其本身表现为一个家族。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Dvije ili više osoba povezane rođenjem, brakom, posvojenjem ili sličnim zakonskim statusom ili koje se na koji drugi način predstavljaju kao obitelj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Dvě či více osoby příbuzné narozením, sňatkem, adopcí nebo podobným legálním statusem, či prezentující se jako rodina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Plusieurs personnes liées par la naissance, le mariage, l’adoption, ou un statut légal similaire, ou qui se présentent elles-mêmes comme formant une famille.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Zwei oder mehr Personen, die durch Geburt, Heirat, Adoption oder einen vergleichbaren gesetzlichen Status miteinander in Beziehung stehen oder sich als eine Familie darstellen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Due o più persone imparentate per nascita, matrimonio, adozione o stati legali affini o altrimenti che si presentano come una famiglia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">出生、婚姻、養子縁組もしくは同様の法的地位によって関連付けられた、または自らを家族であるとする2以上の個人。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">출생, 결혼, 입양, 혹은 유사한 법적 신분으로 관련된 둘 이상의 개인, 혹은 스스로를 하나의 가족으로 표현한 둘 이상의 개인</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Dve ili više osoba koje su povezane rođenjem, brakom, usvajanjem ili sličnim zakonskim statusom, ili koje se na drugi način predstavljaju kao porodica.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Dve alebo viaceré osoby príbuzné narodením, sobášom, adopciou alebo podobným legálnym statusom, alebo prezentujúce sa ako rodina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Dos o más personas relacionadas por nacimiento, matrimonio, adopción o estado legal similar o que, de otra manera, se presentan a sí mismos como familia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Två eller fler personer som är relaterade till varandra genom födelse, äktenskap, adoption eller annan juridisk status eller på annat vis framställer sig själv som en familj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Hai hay nhiều người có quan hệ với nhau về ngày sinh, hôn nhân, nuôi dưỡng hay tình trạng luật pháp tương đồng hay nói cách khác bản thân họ hiện diện như một gia đình.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">บุคคลสองบุคคลขึ้นไปที่มีความสัมพันธ์ด้วยการเกิด การสมรส การรับเป็นญาติบุญธรรม หรือสถานะทางกฎหมายที่คล้ายกัน นอกจากนี้ยังรวมไปถึงการแสดงตนเองเป็นครอบครัว</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Dve ali več oseb, ki so povezane po rojstvu, poroki, posvojitvi ali po podobnem zakonitem razmerju ali pa se same predstavljajo kot rodbina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Co najmniej dwie osoby połączone więzami krwi, małżeństwem, adopcją czy podobnym statusem prawnym lub w inny sposób określających siebie jako rodzinę.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Du ar daugiau asmenų, susijusių gimimo, santuokos, įvaikinimo arba panašiu juridiniu statusu arba kitu būdu pristatančių save kaip giminę.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Divas vai vairākas personas, kuru radniecību nosaka piedzimšana, laulība, adopcija vai līdzīgs juridisks statuss, vai arī, kuras apliecina sevi kā ģimeni/dzimtu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Perhe/suku</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Kaksi tai useampia henkilöitä, joita yhdistää toisiinsa syntyperä, avioliitto, adoption tai vastaava lain mukainen status, tai jotka muulla tavoin esittäytyvät perheenä.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Identifier  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Identifier" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4703"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Identifier</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A number, code, word, phrase, logo, device, etc., that is associated with an entity, and serves to differentiate that entity from other entities within the domain in which the identifier is assigned.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Identifikues</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">المحدد</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Идентификатор</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Identificador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">识别符</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Identifikator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Identifikátor</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Tunniste</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Identifiant</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Identifikator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Identificatore</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">識別子</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">식별기호</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Identifikators</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Identifikatorius</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Identyfikator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Identificador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Идентификатор</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Identifikator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Identifikátor</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Označevalec</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Identificador</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Identifikator</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ตัวระบุ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Đặc điểm nhận dạng</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Số, mã, chữ cái, cụm từ ngữ, logo, hình vẽ,... đi cùng với thực thể giúp phân biệt thực thể này với thực thể khác trong cùng một phạm vi mà đặc điểm nhận dạng được nêu ra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Numër, kod, fjalë, frazë, markë, emblemë, etj., e bashkëlidhur me një entitet dhe shërben për ta dalluar atë nga entitete të tjera brenda fushës të cilës i përket identifikuesi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">رقم، رمز، كلمة، عبارة، شعار، جهاز، الخ. مرتبط بكيان ما، ويخدم متطلبات التمييز بين هذا الكيان وكيانات أخرى ضمن المجال الذي عين وخصص هذا المحدد.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Номер, код, дума, израз, емблема, знак и др., който е свързан с определен обект и служи за разграничеването й от другите обекти в областта, за която е присъден идентификаторът.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Número, codi, paraula, frase, logotip, dispositiu, etc., associat amb una entitat i que serveix per diferenciar-la d’altres entitats dins el domini en el qual s’assigna l’identificador.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">与一个实体相关联的一个数字、代码、词语、短语、图标（logo）、图样等，用以在分配识别符的范畴内将该实体与其它实体区分开来。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Broj, kod, riječ, izraz, logo, uređaj itd., povezan s entitetom, a služi za razlikovanje tog entiteta od drugih entiteta unutar domene u kojoj je dodijeljen identifikator.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Numero, koodi, sana, ilmaus, logo, tunnusmerkki jne., joka liittyy entiteettiin ja erottaa tämän muista entiteeteistä siinä käsitejärjestelmässä (domain), mihin tunnus kuuluu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Numéro, code, mot, locution, logo, indicatif, etc. associé à une entité, et qui vise à différencier cette entité de toute autre entité appartenant au domaine au sein duquel cet identifiant est attribué.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Nummer, ein Code, ein Wort, eine Phrase, ein Logo, eine Vorrichtung etc. die mit einer Entität in Verbindung steht und dazu dient, diese Entität innerhalb des Bereichs, für den der Identifikator definiert ist, von anderen Entitäten zu unterscheiden.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Numero, codice, parola, frase, logo, dispositivo ecc. associato a un’entità e serve a differenziare quell’entità dalle altre all’interno del dominio nel quale l’identificatore è assegnato.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">ある実体と関係づけられ、その識別子が適用されている領域において、その実体と他の実体との区別ができるようにするための番号、コード、語、語句、ロゴ、仕組み等。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체와 관련된 숫자, 부호, 단어, 어구, 로고, 고안 등으로, 할당된 식별기호는 도메인 내에서 해당 개체와 다른 개체를 구별하기 위해 사용된다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Número, código, palavra, frase, logotipo, mecanismo, etc. associado a uma entidade e  que serve para diferenciá-la de outras entidades no contexto em que o identificador é atribuído.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Номер, код, слово, фраза, эмблема, знак и т.п., которые ассоциируются с объектом и помогают отличить этот объект от других объектов в той области, к которой относится данный идентификатор.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Broj, oznaka, reč, fraza, logo, geslo i drugo, povezano sa entitetom i služi za razlikovanje tog entiteta od drugih entiteta u oblasti u okviru koje je identifikator dodeljen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un numero, código, palabra, frase, logotipo, aparato, etc., que se asocia con una entidad y sirve para diferenciar entidades dentro del mismo ámbito en el que se asigna el identificador.  </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Ett nummer, kod, ord, fras, logotyp, figur etc. som är förbunden med en entitet, och gör att denna kan skiljas från andra entiteter inom den domän inom vilken identifikatorn tilldelats.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Numurs, kods, vārds, vārdkopa, emblēma, logo, u.tml., kas ir saistīts ar entītiju un atšķir šo entītiju no citām entītijām attiecīgajā sfērā, kurā šis identifikators ir piešķirts.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Numeris, kodas, žodis, frazė, logotipas, ženklas ir t. t., kurie susiję su entitetu ir padeda atskirti entitetą nuo kitų entitetų toje srityje, kurioje taikomas konkretus identifikatorius.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Ciąg znaków alfanumerycznych (np. numer, kod, słowo, fraza,
logo, znak itd.), który jest związany z jednostką i służy do odróżnienia jej od innych jednostek w zakresie, do którego odnosi się dany identyfikator.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ตัวเลข รหัส คำ วลี ตราสัญลักษณ์ เครื่องมือ และอื่น ๆ ที่มีความเกี่ยวข้องกับเอนทิตีและจำแนกความแตกต่างของเอนทิตีหนึ่งออกจากเอนทิตีอื่น ๆ ภายในอาณาเขตที่ตัวระบุถูกกำหนดไว้</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Číslo, kód, slovo, fráze, logo, deviza atd., které jsou spojeny s entitou a slouží k odlišení entity od jiných entit v rámci okruhu, ve kterém je identifikátor přidělen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Číslo, kód, slovo, fráza, logo, devíza atď., ktoré sú spojené s entitou a slúžia na odlíšenie entity od iných entít v rámci okruhu, v ktorom je identifikátor pridelený.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Številka, koda, beseda, besedna zveza, znak, znamenje itn., ki je povezano z entiteto in omogoča razlikovanje med posameznimi entitetami znotraj področja, kjer je označevalec veljaven.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Item  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Item" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4704"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Item</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A single exemplar of a manifestation.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Njësi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الوعاء</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Физическа единица</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Ítem</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">单件</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Jedinica građe</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Jednotka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Kappale</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Item</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Exemplar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Esemplare</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">個別資料</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">개별자료</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Vienība</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Vienetas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Egzemplarz</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Item</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Физическая единица </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Jedinica građe</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Jednotka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Enota</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Ejemplar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Exemplar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">หน่วยรายการ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Ấn phẩm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một bản mẫu đơn của cách biểu thị.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">สำเนารูปแบบการเผยแพร่</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Një ekzemplar i vetëm i një manifestimi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نموذج واحد من المظهر.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Отделен екземпляр от форма на физическо представяне.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Exemplar sol d’una manifestació.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一种载体表现的单一样本。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pojedinačni primjerak pojavnog oblika.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Manifestaation yksittäinen esimerkki.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Exemplaire isolé d’une manifestation.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein einzelnes Stück einer Erscheinungsform.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Singola copia di una manifestazione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">体現形の単一の例示。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">구현형에 대한 하나의 사례</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Exemplar individual de uma manifestação.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Один экземпляр воплощения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pojedinačni primerak pojavnog oblika.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una sola unidad de una manifestación.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En enskild representation av en manifestation.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Jednotlivý exemplář provedení.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Atsevišķs manifestācijas eksemplārs.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vienas apraiškos egzempliorius.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Pojedynczy przejaw materializacji.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Jednotlivý exemplár prezentácie.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Posamezni primerek pojavne oblike.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Key title  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#KeyTitle" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4705"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Key title</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The unique name assigned to a continuing resource by the ISSN Network and inseparably linked with its ISSN. The key title may be the same as the title proper; or, in order to achieve uniqueness, it can be constructed by the addition of identifying and/or qualifying elements, such as name of issuing body, place of publication, edition statement.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Titull kyç</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">العنوان المفتاحي</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Ключово заглавие</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Títol clau</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">识别题名</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Ključni naslov</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Klíčový název</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Avainnimeke</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Titre clé</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Key Title</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Titolo chiave</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">キータイトル</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">등록표제</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Atslēgnosaukums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Registracinė antraštė</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Tytuł kluczowy</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Título-chave</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Ключевое заглавие </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Ključni naslov</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Kľúčový názov</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Ključni naslov</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Título clave</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Nyckeltitel</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ชื่อเรื่องหลัก</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Nhan đề chính</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tên duy nhất được nêu ra trong nguồn lực tiếp tục bởi mạng lưới ISSN và liên kết một cách chắc chắn với ISSN của nó. Nhân đề chính có thể giống với tên thường gọi, hoặc để nhằm đạt đươc tính thống nhất, nó có thể được xây dựng bằng cách bổ sung các nhân tố xác định và hoặc nhân tố điều kiện, ví dụ như tên của cơ quan phát hành, nơi xuất bản, lần xuất bản.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Título único asignado a un recurso continuado por la Red ISSN y unido inseparablemente al ISSN. El título clave puede coincidir con el título propiamente dicho o, a fin de que sea inequívoco, se puede construir mediante la adición de elementos identificadores y/o calificadores, tales como el nombre de la entidad editora, el lugar de publicación, la mención de edición.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Emri unik i caktuar për një burim në vazhdim nga Rrjeti ISSN dhe i lidhur në mënyrë të pandashme me ISSN-në e tij. Titulli kyç mund të jetë i njëjtë me titullin kryesor, ose për të arritur unifikim, ai mund të ndërtohet duke shtuar elemente identifikimi dhe/ose kualifikimi, si p.sh. emri i organit që e nxjerr, vendi i botimit, të dhëna për botimin.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">)– الاسم المميز لمصدر مستمر معين من قبل شبكة ISSN ومرتبط بغير انفصال بالترقيم الدولي الموحد للدورية ISSN التابع له. قد يكون العنوان المفتاحي مثل العنوان الرئيسي؛ أو لغرض تمييزه، يمكن بناءه بإضافة عناصر محددة أو مميزة كاسم هيئة الاصدار، مكان النشر، الطبعة، الخ.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Уникално название на продължаващ ресурс, което се определя от Мрежата ISSN ие неразривно свързано с неговия ISSN. Ключовото заглавие може да съвпада с основното заглавие или, за да се постигне уникалност, може да бъде изградено като се добавят елементи за идентификация и/или определение като наименование на организациятаиздател, местоиздаване, сведения за изданието.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Nom únic assignat a un recurs continu per la Xarxa ISSN i lligat inseparablement al seu ISSN. El títol clau pot coincidir amb el títol propi o, per assegurar-ne el caràcter únic, es pot elaborar mitjançant l’addició d’elements identificadors i/o qualificadors, com ara el nom de l’entitat editora, el lloc de publicació, la menció d’edició.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">由国际标准连续出版物(ISSN Network)分配给一种连续性资源的唯一名称，与其国际标准连续出版物号(ISSN)密不可分。识别题名可以与正题名相同；或者，为了实现唯一性，可以在设立时附加识别和/或限制成分，比如发行团体名称、出版地、版本说明等。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Jedinstveni naziv koji je jedinici neomeđene građe dodijelila Mreža ISSN i koji je neodvojivo vezan uz ISSN. Ključni naslov može biti jednak glavnom stvarnom naslovu, ili kad ga se želi učiniti jedinstvenim, može biti izgrađen tako da se glavnom stvarnom naslovu doda identifikacijska oznaka i/ili objašnjenje, kao što je naziv izdavača, mjesto izdavanja, podatak o izdanju.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">ISSN-tunnuksen saaneelle jatkuvalle julkaisulle annettu ainutkertainen nimeke, joka liittyy erottamattomasti julkaisun ISSN-tunnukseen. Avainnimeke voi olla sama kuin päänimeke, tai se voidaan ainutkertaisuuden saavuttamiseksi muodostaa lisäämällä päänimekkeeseen sellaisia tunnistamista helpottavia lisämääreitä kuten julkaisevan yhteisön nimi, kustannuspaikka, painosmerkintö.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Nom unique attribué à une ressource continue par le Réseau ISSN et indissociable de son ISSN. Le titre clé peut être identique au titre propre, ou, afin d’assurer son caractère unique, être construit par l’ajout d’éléments d’identification ou de qualification, tels que le nom de la collectivité éditrice, le lieu d’édition, la mention d’édition.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der eindeutige Name, der einer fortlaufenden Ressource durch das ISSN-Netzwerk gegeben wird, und der untrennbar mit der ISSN verbunden ist. Der Key Title kann mit dem Haupttitel identisch sein oder durch Hinzufügen von identifizierenden und/oder qualifizierenden Elementen zum Haupttitel (z. B. Name der herausgebenden Körperschaft, Erscheinungsort, Ausgabebezeichnung etc.) konstruiert werden, um ihn eindeutig und unverwechselbar zu machen (s. ISSN Manual).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Nome univoco assegnato dalla Rete ISSN a una risorsa in continuazione e inseparabilmente legato al suo ISSN. Il titolo chiave può essere uguale al titolo proprio, o, al fine di garantirne l’univocità, può essere strutturato aggiungendo elementi identificativi e/o di qualificazione come il nome dell’ente che la ha emessa, il luogo di pubblicazione, l’indicazione di edizione.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">ISSNネットワークによって継続資料に与えられた固有の名称で、そのISSN番号と不可分に関連付けられたもの。キータイトルは本タイトルと同一の場合もあるが、固有性を得るために、識別要素および／または限定要素、たとえば発行者の名称、出版地、版表示等を付加して構成されることもある。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">ISSN 네트워크에서 계속자료에 부여한 고유한 이름으로서 ISSN자체와 불가분의 관계로 연결되어 있다. 등록표제는 본표제와 동일할 수 있으며, 고유성을 갖기 위해 발행처, 발행지, 판표시와 같은 식별요소 및 한정요소를 부가 할 수 있다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Designação unívoca atribuída a um recurso contínuo pela Rede ISSN e indissociável do respectivo ISSN. O título-chave pode coincidir com o título próprio (principal) ou, de forma a tornar-se unívoco, ser construído pela adição de elementos de identificação ou qualificação tais como nome da entidade editora, lugar de publicação, menção de edição.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Уникальное название, присвоенное продолжающемуся ресурсу службой ISSN и неразрывно связанное с его ISSN. Ключевое заглавие может совпадать с основным заглавием; или, для достижения уникальности, оно может быть сконструировано путем добавления идентифицирующих и/или поясняющих элементов, таких как наименование издающей организации, место издания, сведения об издании.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Jedinstveni naziv koji je Mreža ISSN dodelila kontinuiranom izvoru i koji je neodvojivo povezan sa ISSN brojem. Ključni naslov može da bude isti kao i glavni stvarni naslov, ili, kako bi postigao jedinstvenost, on može da bude izgrađen tako da se glavnom stvarnom naslovu dodaju identifikacioni i/ili kvalifikacioni elementi kao što su nazivi izdavača, mesto izdavanja, podatak o izdanju itd.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Det unika namn ISSN-nätverket tilldelat en seriell resurs, fast länkat till dess ISSN. Nyckeltiteln kan vara densamma som huvudtiteln eller, för att göra den unik, kan olika identifierande och/eller kvalificerande element läggas till, t.ex. utgivarens namn, publikationsort, upplageuppgift.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อเฉพาะที่กำหนดให้กับทรัพยากรต่อเนื่องด้วยเครือข่าย ISSN และเชื่อมโยงอย่างไม่ สามารถแยกออกจาก ISSN ได้ ชื่อเรื่องหลักอาจเป็นชื่อเดียวกับชื่อเรื่องที่เหมาะสม หรือ เพื่อให้เกิดความเป็นหนึ่งเดียว สามารถสร้างชื่อเรื่องหลักจากการเพิ่มองค์ประกอบที่ระบุและ/หรือองค์ประกอบ ที่เหมาะสม เช่น ชื่อหน่วยงานเผยแพร่ สถานที่ตีพิมพ์ ถ้อยคำแสดงครั้งที่ผลิต เป็นต้น</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Jedinečné jméno přidělené pokračujícímu zdroji v rámci ISSN Network a neoddělitelně spojené s jeho číslem ISSN. Klíčový název může být stejný jako hlavní název; nebo může být za účelem dosažení jedinečnosti doplněn o identifikační prvky a/nebo kvalifikátory, jako jsou např. jméno vydavatele, místo vydání, údaj o vydání.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">ISSN sistēmā turpinājumresursam piešķirts unikāls nosaukums, kas nešķirami saistīts ar tā ISSN. Atslēgnosaukums var būt tāds pat kā pamatnosaukums vai neatkārtojamības nolūkā to var veidot, pievienojot identificējošus un/vai paskaidrojošus elementus, piemēram, izdevējinstitūcijas nosaukumu, izdošanas vietu, izdevuma ziņas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vienintelis vardas, kurį tęsiamajam ištekliui nustato ISSN tinklas ir kuris neatskiriamai susijęs su savo ISSN. Registracinė antraštė gali sutapti su pagrindine antrašte arba, siekiant unikalumo, ji gali būti papildyta identifikuojančiais ir (arba) aiškinančiais elementais, tokiais kaip leidžiančiojo kolektyvo vardas, išleidimo vieta, laidos duomenys.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Jednoznaczna nazwa nadana zasobowi ciągłemu przez Sieć
ISSN i nierozerwalnie związana ze swoim (numerem) ISSN. Tytuł kluczowy może być taki sam jak tytuł właściwy lub utworzony przez dodanie elementów
identyfikujących lub kwalifikujących takich jak nazwa wydawcy, miejsce wydania,
oznaczenie wydania.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Jedinečné meno pridelené zdroju na pokračovanie v rámci ISSN Network a neoddeliteľne spojené s jeho číslom ISSN. Kľúčový názov môže byť rovnaký ako hlavný názov, alebo môže byť za účelom dosiahnutia jedinečnosti doplnený o identifikačné prvky a/alebo kvalifikátory, akými sú napr. meno vydavateľa, miesto vydania, údaj o vydaní.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Edinstveni naslov, ki ga kontinuiranemu viru določijo znotraj mreže centrov ISSN in je neločljivo povezan s številko ISSN. Ključni naslov je lahko enak stvarnemu naslovu ali pa mu, zato da se razlikuje od drugih enakih naslovov, dodamo element, ki ga označuje ali opredeljuje, na primer ime izdajatelja, kraj izdaje, vrsto izdaje.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Manifestation  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Manifestation" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4706"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Manifestation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The physical embodiment of an expression of a work.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Manifestim</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">المظهر</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Форма на физическо представяне</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Manifestació</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">载体表现</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Pojavni oblik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Provedení</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Manifestaatio</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Manifestation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Manifestation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Manifestazione</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">体現形</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">구현형</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Manifestācija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Apraiška</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Materializacja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Manifestação</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Воплощение </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Pojavni oblik</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Prezentácia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Pojavna oblika</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Manifestación</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Manifestation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รูปแบบการเผยแพร่</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Sự biểu thị</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là sự thể hiện vật lý của một biểu ngữ của tác phẩm.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ผลประกอบทางกายภาพของรูปแบบการนำเสนองาน</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Den fysiska gestaltningen av ett uttryck för ett verk.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La materialización física de la expresión de una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Materializimi fizik i shprehjes së një vepre. </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">التجسيد المادي لتعبير العمل.
المظهر يمكن أن يشمل مجموعة من الأعمال، أو عمل واحد، أو جزء من عمل، المظاهر يمكن أن تظهر في شكل وحدة مادية واحدة أو أكثر.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Физическо въплъщение на формата на проявление на произведение.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Materialització física de l’expressió d’una obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一部作品的内容表达的物理体现。
载体表现可以体现为作品集、个别作品或者作品的组成部分。载体表现可以以一个或多个物理单位的形式出现。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Fizičko postvarenje izraza djela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Teoksen ekspression fyysinen ilmentymä.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Matérialisation d’une expression d’une œuvre.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Die physische Verkörperung einer Expression eines Werkes.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Materializzazione fisica di un’espressione di un’opera.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">著作の表現形の物理的な具体化。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">저작의 표현형을 물리적으로 구현한 것</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Concretização física de uma expressão de uma obra.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Fizičko ostvarenje izraza dela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Fyzická prezentace vyjádření díla.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Darba izteiksmes fiziskais iemiesojums.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Fizinis kūrinio išraiškos įkūnijimas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Fizyczne urzeczywistnienie realizacji dzieła.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Физическая реализация ыражения произведения.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Fyzická prezentácia vyjadrenia diela.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Utelešenje izrazne oblike dela.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Name  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4707"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A character, word, or group of words and/or characters by which an entity is known.  Includes the words/characters designating a person, family, corporate body; includes the terms by which concepts, objects, events, or places are known; includes the title given to a work, expression, manifestation, or item. Used as the basis for an access point.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ConventionalName"/>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#PreferredName"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Emër</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">اسم</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">حرف أو مجموعة من الكلمات و/أو الأحرف والتي يعرف بها كيان؛ تحتوي على الكلمات/الأحرف الدالة على شخص، عائلة، هيئة؛ المصطلحات التي تعرف بها المفاهيم، الأشياء، الأحداث، أو الأماكن؛ وأيضا تستخدم كأساس لنقطة وصول.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">名称</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Jméno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Nimi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">名称</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">이름</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Vardas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Nazwa</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Meno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Nombre</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Namn</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ชื่อ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Tên</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một ký tự, một chữ, hay nhóm chữ/ký tự mà nhờ đó một thực thể được biết đến. Bao gồm từ/ksy tự chỉ tên cá nhân, gia đình, đoàn thể, bao gồm cả thuật ngữ chỉ khái niệm, vật thể, sự kiện hay địa điểm; bao gồm cả nhan đề của tác phẩm, biểu ngữ, cách biểu thị và ấn phẩm. Tất cả đều được sử dụng như những điểm truy cập.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ตัวอักษร คำ กลุ่มคำและ/หรือกลุ่มตัวอักษรที่ทำให้เอนทิตีเป็นที่รู้จัก ประกอบไปด้วยคำ/ตัวอักษรที่ บ่งชี้ บุคคล ครอบครัว นิติบุคคล; คำที่ทำให้แนวคิด สิ่งของ เหตุการณ์หรือสถานที่เป็นรู้จัก; เช่นเดียวกันกับชื่อเรื่องที่กำหนดให้กับงาน รูปแบบการนำเสนอ รูปแบบการเผยแพร่ หรือหน่วยรายการ ใช้เป็นหลักสำหรับจุดเข้าถึง</skos:definition>
	    <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName"/>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Karakter, fjalë ose grup fjalësh dhe/ose karakteresh me anë të të cilave njihet një entitet. Përfshin fjalët/karakteret që emërtojnë një person, familje, organizëm; termat me anë të të cilave njihen konceptet, objektet, ngjarjet, vendet; titullin që i është dhënë një vepre, shprehjeje, manifestimi ose njësie. Përdoret si bazë për një pikë hyrëse.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Caràcter, paraula o grup de paraules i/o de caràcters pels quals es coneix una entitat. Inclou les paraules/caràcters que designen una persona, família, entitat corporativa; inclou els termes pels quals es coneixen conceptes, objectes, esdeveniments o llocs; inclou el títol assignat a una obra, a una expressió, a una manifestació o a un ítem. S’utilitza com a base d’un punt d’accés.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">用以认识一个实体的一个字符、一个词语，或一组词语和/或字符。包括表示个人、家族、团体的词语/字符；包括用以认识概念、实物、事件或地点的术语；包括为一种作品、内容表达、载体表现或单件所确定的题名。作为检索点的基础。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Znak, riječ ili skup riječi i/ili znakova po kojima je entitet poznat. Uključuje riječi/znakove koji označuju osobu, obitelj, korporativno tijelo; uključuje nazive po kojima su pojmovi, objekti, događaji ili mjesta poznati; uključuje naslov djela, izraza, pojavnog oblika ili jedinice građe. Upotrebljava se kao osnova za pristupnicu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Merkki, sana tai sana- ja/tai merkkiryhmä, jolla entiteetti tunnetaan. Se sisältää sanat/merkit, joiden avulla henkilö perhe/suku, yhteisö nimetään; se sisältää termit, joiden avulla käsitteet, kohteet, tapahtumat tai paikat tunnetaan; se sisältää teoksen, ekspression, manifestaation tai kappaleen nimen. Nimi on hakutiedon perusta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Caractère, mot ou groupe de mots ou de caractères par lequel une entité est connue ; comprend les mots/caractères désignant une personne, une famille, une collectivité ; comprend les termes par lesquels les concepts, les objets, les événements ou les lieux sont connus ; comprend le titre donné à une œuvre, une expression, une manifestation, ou un item. Sert de base pour établir un point d’accès.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Carattere, parola o gruppo di parole e/o caratteri con cui un’entità è conosciuta. Comprende le parole/caratteri che designano una persona, una famiglia, un ente; include i termini con cui concetti, oggetti, eventi o luoghi sono conosciuti; include il titolo dato a un’opera, espressione, manifestazione o esemplare. Usato come base per un punto di accesso.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">それによって実体が知られている文字、あるいは語および／または文字の集まり。個人、家族、団体を指示する語／文字列を含む。概念、物、出来事または場所がそれによって知られる用語を含む。著作、表現形、体現形、または個別資料に付与されたタイトルを含む。アクセスポイントの基礎として使用される。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체를 식별하기 위한 문자나 단어 혹은 일단의 단어나 문자의 집합. 개인이나 가족, 단체를 지칭하는 단어/문자를 포함한다. 개념, 대상, 사건, 장소를 식별하기 위한 용어를 포함한다. 저작이나 표현형, 구현형, 개별자료에 부여된 표제를 포함한다. 접근점의 기초로 사용된다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Caracter, palavra ou grupo de palavras e/ou caracteres pelos quais uma entidade é conhecida; inclui as palavras/caracteres que designam uma pessoa, família, colectividade (entidade); inclui os termos pelos quais são conhecidos conceitos, objetos, eventos ou lugares, assim como o título de uma dada obra, expressão, manifestação ou item. Usado como base para um ponto de acesso.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Znak ili grupa reči i/ili znakova po kojima je entitet poznat. Uključuje reči/znakove koji označavaju osobu, porodicu, kolektivno telo; uključuje termine koji označavaju pojmove, objekte, događaje ili mesta, kao i naslove dela, izraza, pojavnog oblika ili jedinice. Koristi se kao osnova za pristupnu tačku.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un carácter, palabra o grupo de palabras y/o caracteres por el que se conoce a una entidad. Incluye las palabras o caracteres que designan a una persona, familia, entidad corporativa; incluye los términos por los que son conocidos los conceptos, objetos, acontecimientos o lugares; así como el título dado a una obra, expresión, manifestación o ejemplar. Utilizado como base para un punto de acceso</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Ett tecken, ord eller grupp av ord under vilka entiteten är känd. Innefattar de ord/tecken som betecknar en person, familj, institution; innefattar de termer under vilka koncept, objekt, händelser och platser är kända; innefattar titlar på verk, uttryck, manifestationer och exemplar. Används som utgångspunkt för sökingången.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Simbolis, žodis ar žodžių ir (arba) simbolių grupė, pagal kurią atpažįstamas entitetas. Apima žodžius/simbolius, reiškiančius asmenį, giminę, kolektyvą; apima terminus,
reiškiančius sąvokas, objektus, įvykius ar vietas; apima kūrinio, išraiškos, apraiškos ar vieneto antraštę. Vartojamas kaip kreipties elemento pagrindas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Znak, slovo či skupina slov a/nebo znaků, pod kterými je entita známa. Zahrnuje slova/znaky označující osobu, rodinu, korporaci; dále zahrnuje termíny pod kterým jsou známy koncepty, objekty, události či místa; zahrnuje i název daný dílu, vyjádření, provedení, či jednotce. Používá se jako základ selekčního údaje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Znak, slovo alebo skupina slov a/alebo znakov, pod ktorými je entita známa. Zahŕňa slová/znaky označujúce osobu, rodinu, korporáciu; ďalej zahŕňa termíny pod ktorými sú známe koncepty, objekty, udalosti alebo miesta; zahŕňa i názov daný dielu, vyjadreniu, prezentácii alebo jednotke. Používa sa ako základ selekčného údaja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Znak, słowo lub grupa słów i/lub znaków nadana jednostce. Obejmuje: - słowa/znaki oznaczające osobę, rodzinę, ciało zbiorowe; - terminy stanowiące nazwy pojęć, obiektów, wydarzeń czy miejsc; - tytuł nadany dziełu, realizacji, materializacji lub egzemplarzowi. Stanowi podstawę punktu dostępu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Črka, beseda ali več besed in/ali črk, po katerih je entiteta poznana. Vključuje besede/črke, ki označujejo osebo, rodbino, korporacijo; vključuje izraze, ki poimenujejo pojme, predmete, dogodke ali kraje; vključuje naslov, s katerim je poimenovano delo, izrazna oblika, pojavna oblika ali enota. Uporablja se kot osnova vstopne točke.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Име (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Буква, дума или група от думи и/или букви, под които е известен обектът. Включва думи/букви, които означават лице, фамилия, колективен орган. Включва термини, под които са известни понятия, предмети, събития или места. Включва заглавието, определено за произведение, форма на проявление, форма на физическо представяне или физическа единица. Използва се като основа за точка за достъп.</skos:definition>
      <skos:scopeNote xml:lang="de">Der englischsprachige Terminus „name“ kann im Deutschen je nach Kontext mit Bezeichnung, Benennung oder Name übersetzt werden, wobei Bezeichnung für den übergeordneten Terminus steht. Um die Vergleichbarkeit der deutschen Übersetzung mit dem englischsprachigen Original zu erleichtern, wurde im Kontext der Internationalen Katalogisierungsprinzipien durchgehend die deutsche Übersetzung „Name“ gewählt.</skos:scopeNote>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Buchstabe, ein Wort oder eine Gruppe von Wörtern und/oder Buchstaben, unter dem/denen eine Entität bekannt ist. Dies schließt die Wörter/Buchstaben mit ein, die eine Person, Familie oder Körperschaft bezeichnen, die Terme, unter denen Begriffe, Gegenstände, Ereignisse oder Orte bekannt sind ebenso wie die Titel, die einem Werk, einer Expression, einer Manifestation oder einem Exemplar gegeben wurden. Wird als Grundlage für einen Sucheinstieg benutzt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Rakstzīme, vārds vai vārdu un/vai rakstzīmju grupa, pēc kuras entītija ir pazīstama. Termins ietver vārdus/rakstzīmes, kas apzīmē personu, dzimtu, institūciju; tas ietver jēdzienu, objektu, notikumu vai vietu apzīmējumus, kā arī darbam, izteiksmei, manifestācijai vai vienībai piešķirto nosaukumu. Personvārds/nosaukums ir piekļuves punkta pamatā.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Personvārds/nosaukums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Имя (наименование) </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Буква, знак или группа слов и/или букв, с помощью которых распознается объект. Включает слова или буквы, обозначающие лицо, род, организацию; термины, обозначающие концепции, предметы, события или места, а также заглавие произведения, выражения, воплощения или физической единицы.  Служит основой для точки доступа.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="lv">Nosaukums</skos:altLabel>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Object  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Object" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4708"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Object</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A material thing.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Objekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الجسم</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Предмет</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Objecte</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">实物</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Objekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Objekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Esine</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Objet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Gegenstand</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Oggetto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">物</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">대상</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Objekts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Objektas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Obiekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Objeto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Предмет</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Predmet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Objekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Predmet</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Objeto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Objekt</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">สิ่งของ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Vật thể</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là vật mang tính chất vật lý.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">สิ่งของทางวัตถุ</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Ett materiellt ting, ett föremål.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una cosa material.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">사물</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">物体。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Una cosa materiale.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein materielles Objekt.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Réalité matérielle.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Aineellinen luetteloinnin kohde.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一种物质的事物。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Нечто материальное.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Realitat material.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Нещо материално.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Materijalna stvar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">شيء مادي</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Send material.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Coisa material.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Materijalna stvar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Materiální věc.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Materiāla lieta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Materialus daiktas.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Rzecz materialna.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Materiálna vec.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Stvar.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Person  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Person" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4709"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Person</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An individual or a single identity established or adopted by an individual or group. </skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Person</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Identitet individual ose unik i vendosur ose përshtatur nga një individ ose grup.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الشخص</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">فرد أو هوية فردية منشئة أو متبناة من قبل فرد أو مجموعة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Лице</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Индивид или отделна идентичност, установени или възприети от индивид или група.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Persona</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Individu o identitat única establerta o adoptada per un individu o un grup.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">个人</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一个个体的人，或由一个个体的人或群体所设立或采纳的单一识别身份。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Osoba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Osoba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Henkilö</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Personne</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Person</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Individuum oder eine Identität, die von einem Individuum oder einer Gruppe eingeführt oder angenommen wird.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Persona</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">個人</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">개인</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개인 또는 개인이나 집단이 선정하거나 채용한 하나의 신원</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">ひとりの人、またはひとりの人もしくは集団により設定もしくは採用された単一のアイデンティティ。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Persona</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Asmuo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Osoba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Pessoa</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Лицо</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Osoba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Osoba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Oseba</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Persona</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Person</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">บุคคล</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Cá nhân</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một cá nhân riêng biệt hay một đặc điểm đơn lẻ được tạo nên hay được thừa nhận bởi một cá nhân hay một nhóm.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ปัจเจกบุคคลหรือเอกลักษณ์หนึ่งที่สร้างขึ้นและรับมาโดยปัจเจกบุคคลหรือกลุ่ม</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En individ eller en identitet som skapats eller använts av en individ eller grupp.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pojedinac ili pojedinačni identitet koji je uspostavio ili prisvojio pojedinac ili skupina.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Yksilö tai yksilön tai ryhmän vakiintunut tai omaksuttu identiteetti.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Individu ou identité particulière établie ou adoptée par un individu ou un groupe.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Individuo o identità singola stabilita o adottata da un individuo o gruppo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Indivíduo ou uma identidade individual estabelecida ou adotada por um indivíduo ou grupo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Индивидуум или единичная идентификация, установленная или принятая индивидуумом или группой.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un individuo o una única identidad establecida o adoptada por un individuo o grupo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pojedinac ili persona koju je ustanovio ili usvojio pojedinac ili grupa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Individuální či jako individuální se prezentující entita ustanovená nebo přijatá jednotlivcem či skupinou.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Indivīds vai atsevišķa identitāte, ko izveidojis vai pieņēmis kāds indivīds vai grupa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Individas arba vienintelė tapatybė, nusistatyta ar priimta individo arba grupės.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Jednostka ludzka lub pojedyncza tożsamość ustanowiona lub przejęta przez jednostkę lub grupę.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Individuálna alebo ako individuálne sa prezentujúca entita ustanovená alebo prijatá jednotlivcom alebo skupinou.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Posameznik ali posamezna identiteta, ki pripada posamezniku ali skupini ali jo privzameta.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Place  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Place" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4710"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Place</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A location.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Vend</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">المكان</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Място</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Lloc</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">地点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Mjesto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Lokalitet.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">一处场所。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Vendndodhje.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">موضع.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Местонахождение.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Localització.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Místo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Paikka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Lieu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Ort</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Luogo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">場所</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">所在地。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Địa điểm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">สถานที่</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Plats</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Lugar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Kraj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Miesto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Mesto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Место</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Lugar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Miejsce</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Vieta</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Vieta</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">장소</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">위치</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một vị trí địa lí.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ตำแหน่งที่ตั้ง</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En plats.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una localización.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Lokacija.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Lokace.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Coordonnées topographiques (endroit). </skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Ortsangabe.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Località.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Atrašanās vieta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Buvimo vieta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Lokalizacja.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Localização, espaço.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Местонахождение.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Lokácia.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Lokacija.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Preferred name  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#PreferredName" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4711"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Preferred name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The name for an entity chosen according to rules or standards, used as the basis for constructing an authorized access point for the entity.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Emër i preferuar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الاسم المفضل</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Nom preferit</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">首选名称</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Izabrano ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Preferované jméno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Ensisijainen nimi</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Nom privilégié</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Bevorzugter Name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Nome preferito</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">優先される名称</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">채택된 이름</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Prioritetinis vardas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Nome preferido</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Preferentno ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Preferované meno</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Izbrano ime</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Nombre preferido</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Föredraget namn</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ชื่อที่ให้ความสำคัญ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Tên ưu tiên</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Przyjęta nazwa</skos:prefLabel>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">اسم الكيان الذي تم اختياره بناء على قواعد ومعايير، وتم استخدامه لإنشاء نقطة الوصول المقننة للكيان.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Emër i një entiteti i zgjedhur sipas rregullave ose standardeve, i përdorur si bazë për ndërtimin e një pike hyrëse të autorizuar për entitetin.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Nom d’una entitat triat segons unes regles o uns estàndards, utilitzat com a base per elaborar el punt d’accés autoritzat de l’entitat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">根据规则或标准选择的一个实体的名称，用来作为建立该实体规范检索点的基础。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Ime entiteta izabrano prema pravilima ili standardima kojem se daje prednost pri izradi usvojene pristupnice entiteta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Sääntöjen tai standardien mukaan valittu entiteetin nimi, jota käytetään perustana muodostettaessa entiteetin auktorisoitu hakutieto.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Nom d’une entité choisi selon des règles ou des normes, sur lequel on s’appuie pour construire le  point d’accès autorisé pour cette entité.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der Name einer Entität, der gemäß Regeln und Standards ausgewählt wurde, und als Grundlage für die Bildung der Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs für die Entität verwendet wird.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Nome di un’entità scelto in base a regole o standard, impiegato come base per la costruzione di un punto di accesso autorizzato per quella entità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">規則または基準に従って選択され、その実体に対する典拠形アクセスポイントを作成する基礎として用いられる、実体の名称。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">규칙이나 표준에 따라 선정된 개체에 대한 이름으로서 개체에 대한 전거형 접근점을 구성하는 데 기초로 사용된다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Nome de uma entidade escolhido de acordo com regras e normas, usado como base para construir um ponto de acesso autorizado para a entidade.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Ime entiteta izabrano u skladu sa pravilima ili standardima koje se koristi kao osnova za kreiranje normirane pristupne tačke entiteta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">El nombre de una entidad elegida según las reglas o normas usadas como la base para la construcción de un punto de acceso autorizado para dicha entidad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Tên gọi cho một thực thể được lựa chọn dựa trên quy tắc hay tiêu chuẩn, sử dụng làm cơ sở để xây dựng điểm truy cập được phép tới một thực thể.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Det entitetsnamn som valts i enlighet med regler eller standarder, för att utgöra grunden för den auktoriserade sökingång som skapas för entiteten.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Jméno entity vybrané podle pravidel či standardů a použité jako základ pro stanovení autorizovaného selekčního údaje pro entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Entiteto vardas, pasirinktas pagal taisykles arba standartus
ir vartojamas kaip pagrindas sudarant aprobuotą kreipties elementą entitetui.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Nazwa jednostki wybrana zgodnie z przepisami i standardami, stosowana jako podstawa do utworzenia ujednoliconego punktu
dostępu do jednostki.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Meno entity vybrané podľa pravidiel alebo štandardov a použité ako základ pre stanovenie autorizovaného selekčného údaja pre entitu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Ime entitete, izbrano na podlagi pravil in standardov, ki služi kot osnova za oblikovanje normativne vstopne točke do entitete.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ชื่อสำหรับเอนทิตีที่ได้รับการเลือกตามกฎหรือมาตรฐาน ใช้เป็น พื้นฐานในการสร้างจุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้สำหรับเอนทิตี

</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ConventionalName"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Предпочетено име (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Името (наименованието) на обект, избрано в съответствие с правила и стандарти, използвано като основа за съставяне на установената точка за достъп за обекта.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Prioritārais personvārds/nosaukums</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Entītijas personvārds/ nosaukums, kas izraudzīts atbilstoši noteikumiem vai standartiem, kurus izmanto entītijas autorizētā piekļuves punkta izveidē.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Предпочтительное имя (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Имя (наименование) объекта,  выбранное в соответствии с правилами или стандартами и используемое в качестве основы для формирования авторитетной точки доступа  к объекту.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Relationship  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Relationship" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4712"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Relationship</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A specific connection between entities or their instances.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Lidhshmëri</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Marrëdhënie specifike ndërmjet entiteteve.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">علاقة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">صلة معينة بين الكيانات أو مثيلاتها.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Връзка</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Специфично отношение между обектите и техните проявления.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Relació</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Enllaç específic entre entitats o les seves exemplificacions.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">关系</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">实体之间或其实例之间的特定连接。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Odnos</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Posebna veza između entiteta.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Vztah</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Suhde</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Entiteettien tai niitä edustavien esimerkkien välinen tarkoin määritelty suhde.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Relation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Lien spécifique entre des entités ou leurs instances.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Beziehung</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine bestimmte Verbindung zwischen Entitäten oder ihren Instanzen.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">関連</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">実体間または実体のインスタンス間の特定の結びつき。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">관계</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체와 그 사례 간의 특수한 연관성</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Attiecība</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Santykis</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Relacja</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Relação</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ligação específica entre duas entidades ou suas instâncias.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Связь</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Особые отношения между объектами или их   проявлениями.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Odnos</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Vzťah</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Odnos</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Relación</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una conexión específica entre entidades o  sus ejemplicaciones.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Relation</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En specifik koppling mellan entiteter eller instanser av entiteter.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">ความสัมพันธ์</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">การเชื่อมโยงเฉพาะระหว่างเอนทิตีหรือตัวแทนของเอนทิตี</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Mối quan hệ</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một mối liên kết cụ thể giữa các thực thể hay các khía cạnh khác nhau của chúng.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Specifické spojení mezi entitami či jejich instancemi.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Konkrēta saistība starp entītijām vai to piemēriem.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Specifinis ryšys tarp entitetų ir jų pavyzdžių.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Określony związek pomiędzy jednostkami lub ich wystąpieniami.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Posebna veza između entiteta ili njihovih primeraka.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Specifična povezava med entitetami ali njihovimi primerki.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Špecifické spojenie medzi entitami alebo ich inštanciami.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Subject cataloguing  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#SubjectCataloguing" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4713"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Subject cataloguing</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The part of cataloguing that provides controlled subject terms and/or classification numbers.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#DescriptiveCataloguing"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Katalogim lëndor</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الفهرسة الموضوعية</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Съдържателна каталогизация</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Catalogació de matèries</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">主题编目</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Predmetna katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pjesë e katalogimit që përcakton termat e subjektit të kontrolluara dhe/ose numrat e klasifikimit.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">جزء الفهرسة المزود لرؤوس الموضوعات/المصطلحات و/أو أرقام التصنيف.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Частта от каталогизацията, която осигурява контролирани предметни рубрики/термини и/или класификационни индекси.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Part de la catalogació que proporciona termes controlats de matèries i/o números de classificació.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">编目工作的组成部分，提供受控的主题词和/或分类号。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Dio katalogizacije koji osigurava nadzirane predmetnice i/ili klasifikacijske oznake.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Věcná katalogizace</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Sisällönkuvailu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Sisällönkuvailussa tietueeseen lisätään kontrolloidut asiasanat ja/tai luokitusnotaatiot.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Catalogage matière</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Partie du catalogage qui établit à la fois les mots matière contrôlés ou les indices de classification.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Sacherschließung</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Der Teil der Erschließung, der Schlagworte vergibt und/oder klassifiziert.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Catalogazione per soggetto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Parte della catalogazione che fornisce termini per intestazioni di soggetto e/o numeri di classificazione controllati.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">主題目録作業</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">目録作業において、主題を表す統制された語および／または分類記号を与える部分</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">주제목록법</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">제어형 주제어 및 분류기호를 제시하는 목록기법의 한 영역</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Priekšmetošana</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Dalykinis ir sisteminis katalogavimas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Katalogowanie rzeczowe</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Catalogação de assunto </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Содержательная каталогизация </skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Predmetna katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Vecná katalogizácia</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Vsebinska katalogizacija</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Catalogación por materias</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Deo katalogizacije koji obezbeđuje kontrolisane predmetne odrednice i/ili klasifikacione brojeve.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">La parte de la catalogación que proporciona los términos controlados de materias y/o números de clasificación.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Ämneskatalogisering</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Den del av katalogiseringen som redovisar kontrollerade ämnesord och/eller klassifikationskoder.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">การลงรายการเชิงหัวเรื่อง</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">ส่วนหนึ่งของการลงรายการที่กำหนดหัวเรื่องที่ได้รับการ ควบคุมและ/หรือเลขหมวดหมู่</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Biên mục chủ đề</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là một phần của công tác biên mục cung cấp thuật ngữ chủ đề có kiểm soát và/hoặc số phân loại.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Kataloģizācijas darba daļa, kas nodrošina priekšmetu kontrolētu apzīmējumu un/vai klasificēšanas indeksu piešķiršanu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Katalogavimo dalis, kuri pateikia
kontroliuojamus dalykinius terminus ir (arba) klasifikacinius indeksus.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Część katalogowania, która obejmuje kontrolowane słownictwo rzeczowe i/lub symbole klasyfikacji.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Parte da catalogação que fornece termos de assunto controlados e/ou números de classificação.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Часть каталогизации, которая обеспечивает контролируемые предметные рубрики/термины и/или классификационные индексы.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Del katalogizacije, povezan s kontroliranimi predmetnimi oznakami in/ali klasifikacijskimi številkami.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Část katalogizace, která vytváří řízené věcné termíny a/nebo klasifikační znaky.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Časť katalogizácie, ktorá vytvára riadené vecné termíny a/alebo klasifikačné znaky.</skos:definition>
      <skos:altLabel xml:lang="pt">Indexação por assuntos</skos:altLabel>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Uncontrolled access point  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#UncontrolledAccessPoint" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4716"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Uncontrolled access point</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">An access point that is not controlled by an authority record.</skos:definition>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse e pakontrolluar</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">نقطة الوصول غير المضبوطة</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Неконтролирана точка за достъп</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés no controlat</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">非受控检索点</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Nenadzirana pristupnica</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Neřízený selekční údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Kontrolloimaton hakutieto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès non contrôlé</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Nicht normierter Sucheinstieg</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso non controllato</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">非統制形アクセスポイント</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">비제어형 접근점</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Nekontrolētais piekļuves punkts</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Nekontroliuojamas kreipties elementas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Niekontrolowany punkt dostępu</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso não controlado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Неконтролируемая точка доступа</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Slobodno oblikovana pristupna tačka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Neriadený selekčný údaj</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Nekontrolirana vstopna točka</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Punto de acceso no controlado</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Okontrollerad sökingång</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงแบบไม่ควบคุม</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Điểm truy cập không được kiểm soát</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Một điểm truy cập không được kiểm soát bởi biểu ghi tiêu đề chuẩn.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">จุดเข้าถึงที่ไม่ถูกควบคุมด้วยรายการควบคุม</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Pikë hyrëse që nuk është kontrolluar nga një regjistrim termi të njësuar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">نقطة وصول غير مضبوطة بواسطة تسجيلة استنادية</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Точка за достъп, която не е контролирана от контролен запис.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Punt d’accés que no està controlat per un registre d’autoritat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">并非由规范记录所控制的检索点。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Pristupnica koja nije nadzirana preglednim zapisom.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Hakutieto, jota ei ole auktorisoitu auktoriteettitietueessa.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Point d’accès qui n’est pas contrôlé par une notice d’autorité.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Ein Sucheinstieg, der nicht durch einen Normdatensatz kontrolliert wird.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Punto di accesso non controllato da una registrazione di autorità.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">典拠レコードによって統制されていないアクセスポイント。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">전거레코드에서 제어되지 않은 접근점</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Ponto de acesso que não é controlado por um registo de autoridade.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Точка  доступа, которая не контролируется авторитетной записью.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Pristupna tačka koja nije kontrolisana normativnim zapisom.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Un punto de acceso que no está controlado por un registro de autoridad.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En sökingång som inte kontrolleras av en auktoritetspost.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Selekční údaj, který není řízen autoritním záznamem.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Piekļuves punkts, kas nav reglamentēts autoritatīvajā ierakstā.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Kreipties elementas, kuris nėra kontroliuojamas autoritetinio įrašo.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Punkt dostępu, który nie jest
kontrolowany przez rekord wzorcowy.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Selekčný údaj, ktorý nie je riadený autoritatívnym záznamom.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Vstopna točka, ki ni kontrolirana z normativnim zapisom.</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Variant form of name  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#VariantFormOfName" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4714"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Variant form of name</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A form of name not chosen as the authorized access point for an entity.  It may be used to access the authority record for the entity or be presented as a link to the authorized access point.</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Variant i formës së emritalb</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">الشكل المختلف للاسم</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Вариантна форма на име (наименование)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Forma variant del nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">名称的变异形式</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Neusvojeni oblik imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Variantní forma jména</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Nimen varianttimuoto</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Variante de forme d’un nom</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Abweichende Form des Namens</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Forma variante del nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">名称の異なる形</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">이형의 이름</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Personvārda/nosaukuma atšķirīgā forma</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Vardo formos variantas</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Wariant formy nazwy</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Forma variante de nome</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Вариантная форма имени (наименования)</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Varijantni oblik imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Variantná forma mena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Variantna oblika imena</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Forma variante del nombre</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Variantform av namn</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">รูปแบบชื่ออื่น</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Dạng biến thể của tên</skos:prefLabel>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AuthorizedFormOfName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ControlledAccessPoint"/>
	    <skos:related rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#ConventionalName"/>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Name"/>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Formë e emrit që nuk është zgjedhur si pikë hyrëse e autorizuar për një entitet. Ajo mund të përdoret për të akcesuar regjistrimin e termit të njësuar për entitetin ose të jetë e pranishme si lidhje me pikën hyrëse të autorizuar.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">شكل الاسم الذي لم يتم اختياره كنقطة وصول مقننة للكيان والذي يمكن أن يستخدم للوصول للتسجيلة الاستنادية للكيان أو يعرض كإحالة أو رابط لنقطة الوصول المقننة.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Forma del nom no triada com a punt d’accés autoritzat d’una entitat. Es pot utilitzar per accedir al registre d’autoritat de l’entitat o es pot presentar com un enllaç al punt d’accés autoritzat.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">未被选为实体规范检索点的名称形式。可用于检索实体的规范记录，或者连接规范检索点。</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Oblik imena koji nije izabran kao usvojena pristupnica za entitet. Može se upotrijebiti za pristup preglednom zapisu za entitet ili za prikaz kao poveznica autoriziranoj pristupnici.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Nimimuoto, jota ei ole valittu entiteetin auktorisoiduksi hakutiedoksi. Sitä voidaan käyttää entiteetin auktoriteettitietueen löytämiseksi tai linkkinä auktorisoituun hakutietoon.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine Namensform, die nicht als Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs einer Entität gewählt wurde. Sie kann dafür genutzt werden, um auf den Normdatensatz für die Entität zuzugreifen oder kann als Link zur Ansetzungsform des Sucheinstiegs dargestellt werden.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Forme d’un nom autre que celle choisie comme point d’accès autorisé pour une entité. Elle peut servir de point d’accès à la notice d’autorité de l’entité ou se présenter comme un lien vers le point d’accès autorisé pour cette entité.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Forma del nome non scelta come punto di accesso autorizzato per un’entità. Può essere usato per accedere alla registrazione di autorità dell’entità o essere presentato come collegamento al punto di accesso autorizzato.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">実体に対する典拠形アクセスポイントとして選択されない名称の形。その実体の典拠レコードへのアクセスに使用される、または典拠形アクセスポイントへのリンクとして提示されることがある。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">개체의 전거형 접근점으로 선정되지 않은 이름의 형식으로서, 개체의 전거레코드에 접근하기 위해 사용될 수 있으며, 혹은 전거형 접근점으로 연결하기 위해 제시될 수 있다.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Forma de nome não escolhida como ponto de acesso autorizado para uma entidade. Pode ser usada para aceder (acessar) ao registo de autoridade da entidade ou ser apresentada como ligação para o ponto de acesso autorizado.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Oblik imena koji nije izabran kao normirana pristupna tačka entiteta. Može da se koristi za pristup normativnom zapisu entiteta ili predstavlja vezu sa normiranom pristupnom tačkom.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una forma del nombre de la entidad no elegida como punto de acceso autorizado que se puede utilizar para acceder al registro de autoridad de la entidad o que se puede presentar como un vínculo con el punto de acceso autorizado.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">Namnform som inte valts som auktoriserad sökingång för entiteten. Den kan användas för att nå entitetens auktoritetspost eller utgöra en länk till den auktoriserade sökingången.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là hình thức của tên không được chọn để làm điểm truy cập được phép tới một thực thể. Nó có thể dùng để truy cập tới biểu ghi tiêu đề chuẩn của một thực thể hoặc là đường dẫn tới điểm truy cập được phép.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Може да бъде използвана като достъп до контролния запис за обекта или да бъде представена като препратка към установената точка за достъп.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Forma jména nezvolená za autorizovaný selekční údaj pro entitu. Může být použita pro zpřístupnění autoritního záznamu pro entitu nebo být prezentována jako propojení na autorizovaný selekční údaj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Personvārda/nosaukuma forma, kas nav izraudzīta par entītijas autorizēto piekļuves punktu. To var izmantot, lai piekļūtu entītijas autorizētajam ierakstam vai kā saiti uz autorizēto piekļuves punktu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Vardo forma, nepasirinkta kaip aprobuotas kreipties elementas entitetui. Ji gali būti vartojama kaip kreipties priemonė į autoritetinį įrašą entitetui arba pateikiama kaip saitas į aprobuotą kreipties elementą.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Forma nazwy nie wybrana na ujednolicony punkt dostępu do jednostki. Może zostać użyta, aby dać dostęp do rekordu
wzorcowego jednostki lub prezentowana jako odesłanie do ujednoliconego punktu dostępu.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Форма имени (наименования), которая не выбрана в качестве авторитетной точки доступа для объекта. Она может быть использована для доступа к авторитетной записи для объекта или представлена как отсылка к авторитетной точке доступа.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Forma mena nezvolená za autorizovaný selekčný údaj pre entitu. Môže byť použitá na sprístupnenie autoritatívneho záznamu pre entitu, alebo môže byť prezentovaná ako prepojenie na autorizovaný selekčný údaj.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Oblika imena, ki ni izbrana za normativno vstopno točko do entitete. Lahko jo uporabljamo za dostop do normativnega zapisa za entiteto ali pa za povezavo do normativne vstopne točke.</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">รูปแบบชื่อที่ไม่ถูกเลือกเป็นจุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้ของเอนทิตี อาจ นำมาใช้เข้าถึงรายการควบคุมของเอนทิตี หรือนำมาแสดงเป็นจุดเชื่อมโยงไปยังจุดเข้าถึงที่กำหนดให้ใช้ได้
</skos:definition>
	    <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#AccessPoint"/>
    </skos:Concept>
<!-- Concept: Work  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat#Work" xml:lang="en">
      <skos:inScheme rdf:resource="http://iflastandards.info/ns/muldicat"/>
      <reg:status rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001"/>
      <reg:identifier rdf:resource="http://metadataregistry.org/concepts/4715"/>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Work</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="en">A distinct intellectual or artistic creation (i.e., the intellectual or artistic content).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sq">Vepër</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sq">Krijim i veçantë intelektual ose artistik (që është përmbajtja intelektuale ose artistike).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ar">العمل</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ar">إبداع فكري أو فني مميز (أي، المحتوى الفكري أو الفني).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="bg">Произведение</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="bg">Самостоятелна интелектуална или художествена творба (т.е. интелектуално или художествено съдържание).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ca">Obra</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ca">Creació intel•lectual o artística distinta (és a dir, el contingut intel•lectual o artístic).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="zh">作品</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="zh">独有的知识或艺术的创作（即知识或艺术的内容）。</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="hr">Djelo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="hr">Određena intelektualna ili umjetnička kreacija (tj., intelektualni ili umjetnički sadržaj).</skos:definition>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="cs">Dílo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fi">Teos</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="fr">Œuvre</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="de">Werk</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="it">Opera</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ja">著作</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ko">저작</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lv">Darbs</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="lt">Kūrinys</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pl">Dzieło</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="pt">Obra</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="ru">Произведение</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sr">Delo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sk">Dielo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sl">Delo</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="es">Obra</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="sv">Verk</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="th">งาน</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="vi">Tác phẩm</skos:prefLabel>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fi">Yksittäinen tiedollinen tai taiteellinen luomus (i.e., tiedollinen tai taiteellinen sisältö).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="fr">Création intellectuelle ou artistique déterminée (c’est-à-dire le contenu intellectuel ou artistique).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="de">Eine einzelne intellektuelle oder künstlerische Schöpfung (d. h. der intellektuelle oder künstlerische Inhalt).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="it">Creazione intellettuale o artistica distinta (ossia, il contenuto intellettuale o artistico).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ja">個別の知的・芸術的創造（すなわち、知的・芸術的内容）。　　</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ko">독창성을 지닌 지적 혹은 예술적 창작물(예, 지적 혹은 예술적 내용)</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pt">Criação intelectual ou artística distinta (isto é, o conteúdo intelectual ou artístico).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="ru">Индивидуальное интеллектуальное или художественное творение (т. е., интеллектуальное или художественное содержание).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sr">Određena intelektualna ili umetnička kreacija (to jest, intelektualni ili umetnički sadržaj).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="es">Una creación intelectual o artística diferenciada (es decir, el contenido intelectual o artístico).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sv">En avgränsad intellektuell eller konstnärlig skapelse (det vill säga det intellektuella eller konstnärliga innehållet).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="th">การสร้างสรรค์ทางสติปัญญาและศิลปะ (เช่น เนื้อหาทางสติปัญญาหรือศิลปะ)</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="vi">Là sự sáng tạo mang tính nghệ thuật và trí tuệ đặc trưng (ví dụ như nội dung nghệ thuật hay nội dung trí tuệ).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sl">Intelektualna ali umetniška stvaritev (se pravi, intelektualna ali umetniška vsebina).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="sk">Určitý intelektuálny alebo umelecký výtvor (t. j. intelektuálny alebo umelecký obsah).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="pl">Odrębny wytwór intelektualny lub artystyczny (tzn. o intelektualnej lub artystycznej zawartości).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lt">Odrębny wytwór intelektualny lub artystyczny (tzn. o intelektualnej lub artystycznej zawartości).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="lv">Odrębny wytwór intelektualny lub artystyczny (tzn. o intelektualnej lub artystycznej zawartości).</skos:definition>
      <skos:definition xml:lang="cs">Určitý intelektuální či umělecký výtvor (tj. intelektuální či umělecký obsah).</skos:definition>
    </skos:Concept>

<!-- Status properties used in this document  -->
    <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://metadataregistry.org/uri/RegStatus/1001">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Published</skos:prefLabel>
    </skos:Concept>

</rdf:RDF>
